Krish NAik: Yeah, hello everyone, I'm audible unlocked, just…
Krish NAik: check the chats are opened or not, so I think… War stone, yes.
Krish NAik: Just wait, I think… the cam is not switching on, just wait, some zoom issues, it looks like. Okay, now better, yes.
Krish NAik: All right, so guys, today we'll be continuing our graph, right? So, last Sunday I canceled the class. Okay, so the same thing that we'll be doing the continuation today, but, a few more things that I want to discuss.
Krish NAik: Last, Saturday, I hope everybody has attended the class, because the installation steps with respect to Nino 4G, I won't be repeating. The idea is that you guys are comfortable with the installation, at least in the local part. Yes? For everyone? Right.
Krish NAik: Alright, so today, we'll be talking about… a little bit about the graph rack, like, why GraphRack?
Krish NAik: Now, what was the intuition of GraphTrack? Like, the paper comes from Microsoft, but where everybody got that particular intuition? Before the GraphTrack paper, exactly what happened?
Krish NAik: Okay, and a few things. So, most of those things are related to research, so yes, I'll be sharing the research papers. Please check your Notion. I think, last class already, I've updated those things, but please open Notion once.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me start sharing my screen, just to… So, this is mine,
Krish NAik: Where is my motion?
Krish NAik: Just YouTube.
Krish NAik: Alright, so the motion is…
Krish NAik: This is the last class, same content. Okay, so probably the date will be different, but, just be sure it will be pretty much the same one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, 1st March, now the same thing that I will add it here. Today's date, what's today's date?
Krish NAik: 7th March, I think.
Krish NAik: Yes, I'm talking…
Krish NAik: All right. Now, once you open here, so, first of all, this is the Saturday content, and the seventh one, I will be updating it for 7th one.
Krish NAik: Fully.
Krish NAik: So, this is the other thing that I will be discussing. Now, before that, I want to focus on this part. Hi, because whenever you are building a graph rag, okay, you need to work with ontologies.
Krish NAik: Now, how many of you know the meaning of ontology? This is very, very important.
Krish NAik: Because otherwise, the purpose of building graph racks, there is no purpose.
Krish NAik: Okay, and from where this concept of ontology came, like, how many of you really, like, ontology, simply a rulebook in simple terms, if I try to say?
Krish NAik: Alright, a rulebook with the relations, alright? If you're not, then fine, I'll be talking about that. Because, see, most of you are telling, yes, aware.
Krish NAik: According to normal English language, yes.
Krish NAik: According to normal English, like, according to RAC, the concept of ontology doesn't change, it's just pretty much the same stuff.
Krish NAik: Now, step by step, it means that why one… why I want to focus on this part, because you have to understand, till that time you are not working with some level of ontology, then there is no purpose of building Grafta.
Krish NAik: So, to build a graph rag, okay, I want to focus on the other paper also, because before GraphRag, the first paper that came around.
Krish NAik: It was the OG rack from Microsoft, the same. Okay, and I hope everybody understands the meaning of OG.
Krish NAik: Okay, the actual original stuff. Okay, so I'm just bringing that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the first paper around, like, the main innovative, because just after GraphRat, they put a lot of focus on this particular paper.
Krish NAik: And it's from Microsoft, the entire GraphRad family, you have to understand any type of papers, it's majorly from Microsoft only. No other organization has done much more depth research.
Krish NAik: Because after GraphRag, there was a paper on, lazy graph rag, then the OG rag, okay? So, these are all graph-related papers, and why they put a focus a lot? Because if you're not working with the ontology, it becomes a very, problematic stuff.
Krish NAik: Okay, so a little bit about how to build this particular ontology. Okay, and a few people are telling what is ontology, fine. I'll be coming to that. But, I have shared these links. Please go through this, because more than 4 to 5 papers are there. Every paper I cannot discuss, but,
Krish NAik: This is from here, the core idea, like, things, how it inputs, and why ontology plays a crucial role, that's why I've shared this people, so that you understand that he is really, like, based on that, there is academic research which has been done, and you can spend some time.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's start with the theoretical part, like, what is ontology, why it is required in graph rag, and without defining an ontology, like, it's simply, like, waste of time, I can say. GraphRags, in small, like, if you have not really defined ontology, and if your set of documents is small, it will work.
Krish NAik: But with respect to time, if it keeps on growing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you have to understand that slowly, slowly, you are reaching towards complete failure.
Krish NAik: A complete failure. It means that from 10 documents fine, 100 documents, I will say it's pretty much messy. Your graph will be very much messy. Graph means the knowledge graph.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then finally, like, once you reach 1,000 documents, that's complete failure.
Krish NAik: Okay, so step-by-step, we'll be talking about that. So that's why, with respect to the academia, a little bit, let's talk about. So, how you want to build this particular relationship.
Krish NAik: And I think the last ripple, I think in the last class,
Krish NAik: that GraphRag repo I have shared.
Krish NAik: Okay, just wait, let me open the GitHub one.
Krish NAik: This is the kit.
Krish NAik: So, I've created a simple markdown document by… I think everybody has access to the reports, the same report that in the last class we have discussed with respect to Langchain. There, I have added a markdown file.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is one GraphRackOntologist.md. I'm sharing again. Please open this, and I want you guys to at least
Krish NAik: To do the visualization, because I have picked up only two use cases, and the main focus was for this particular stuff, because here it's directly written, rather than picking anything, the generic way of building any type of knowledge bases.
Krish NAik: once this is done, then only the next step is GraphRag. Without this, you should not work on GraphRack, okay?
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me just take my notes, and let's start over.
Krish NAik: King, it is judged or not judged.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please, like, open the GitHub link that I have shared, first of all.
Krish NAik: Everybody is open.
Krish NAik: I think the black color is fine, or should I go ahead with the white color? I'm gonna have to change, I think, something.
Krish NAik: I feel the white is better when teaching in class.
Krish NAik: Yes, for a live class, it's better, but my personal preference is Okay.
Krish NAik: I think I just checked now.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Alright, the visualization will be better.
Krish NAik: Because, again, you have to understand, the thing that I am trying to discuss, it's highly related to this, ontologies and knowledge graphs, okay? So, the first step, when I say, what is ontology?
Krish NAik: So let's try to go through the basics. What is the meaning of ontology in simplest terms?
Krish NAik: Yes, everyone.
Krish NAik: According to you, because most of you told that, yes, we know, but again, like, I want to really understand.
Krish NAik: Nick.
Krish NAik: Because in simple terms, if I say it's a set of rules, okay, in your book that you define, that yes, these are the rules that needs to be followed, you cannot go anything outside this.
Krish NAik: Can I hear that?
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Yes or no, with respect to any type of rule definition. It means that, say, it's a simple rulebook, and in that rulebook, you'll be writing your own rules.
Krish NAik: Now, to write any type of rules, you need something.
Krish NAik: the basic building blocks, if I say, like a LEGO. For example, if I'm building a city, okay, I need the basic building blocks. Now, what are those basic building blocks? Can I say those are nodes?
Krish NAik: Because without the node, you cannot build any graph, or rather anything. So, those nodes, the first thing. The definition of the notes. So, first of all, the document ontology part, which is written here, okay, it means that I will try to define what are my main nodes.
Krish NAik: Okay, now the same thing that I have written here, okay? Now I have taken a simple problem statement of financial documents.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the first example, and I think the second example that I have taken, it is with respect to social media stuff, okay? So, anyone can relate, because for any type of use cases with respect to GraphRag, you need to focus on the first part. So you need to define your notes.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, nodes… and agents.
Krish NAik: Now, when I'm talking about… so, in this rulebook, we'll be defining the first set
Krish NAik: Which is the type of note. So, in a financial document, when I'm telling, okay, the risk factor, okay, now from this document, you'll be getting chunk.
Krish NAik: Then comes, like, executive slash board member, and everything, you can see that there is this part of. Now, the document
Krish NAik: If I say it, now this chunk is actually a part of the document, so that's why there is a link with respect to Partalk. In that way, for every chunk within a document, you can actually create a relationship, yes or no.
Krish NAik: Now, in that document, what is, like, it's containing? One is risk factor.
Krish NAik: You have to understand, these are basically the nodes, and these are basically the edges.
Krish NAik: node and edges. Now, this is a relationship that needs to be defined.
Krish NAik: Without this, you cannot really understand. So whenever you are working with any set of documents, because till now I've not built the knowledge graph, the next step, once this is the founding blocks, whenever we are working with any type of graph.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the rule. So, in my rulebook, okay, I'm telling that, okay, now all these chunks for the document, now there is a relationship, it's like part of.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then in the next step, what the document contains, again, with that particular note, in that document about something that is mentioned about… okay, now the question comes, how you can find these type of things within a document. Can I say that you can use any type of entity relationship
Krish NAik: models, like NER in simple terms.
Krish NAik: named entity recognized. Otherwise, it's very hard. You need a… most of the times, a generic NER model can do it.
Krish NAik: But I feel that if your data is really, like, niche data, domain-specific data, probably the generic NER models won't work. Then, in those cases, you probably might need to build your own custom NER model also. Now, this is a little bit problematic. It means that
Krish NAik: Before this, there is another set, which is actually the NER. If the NER fails.
Krish NAik: it becomes a problem. It means that you really need to identify these things, which are the actual entities.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, that's why then comes your financial metrics, like, okay, EBITDA ratio, EPS. Now, all this information are extracted from the document, so you have to really understand that your NER model should be very good. Now, the question comes, do you want
Krish NAik: to use LLM here.
Krish NAik: Because that is the other way around, you know, that if you don't have a model, you cannot. You can actually pass that same setup
Krish NAik: information to the LLM, and you can ask the LLM to do the extraction. I can say that, yes, you can do it. But again, the LLM should be aware of that particular knowledge. Like, generic, it works. But again, for domain-specific data, you have to do the research that whether that particular LLM can do it or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, so really, so for domain-specific data, only it becomes a problem. For generic data, you won't be facing such problems.
Krish NAik: All it. Now, if I…
Krish NAik: Okay, so now this is the first part where you actually define the nodes and the edges, okay? Now, once the nodes and the edges has been defined.
Krish NAik: Can you see here, allowed type edges. Now, for example, if I say this part of, this is an edge, okay? And the nodes are, for example, this one, chunk, risk factor. Now, these are the major nodes, if I…
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes your financial metric, corporate event, risk factor, regulation, these are all. Is this part clear, the first step that you define in a document?
Krish NAik: Whenever you have a PDF document with you.
Krish NAik: Okay, now just think about, you have done the chunking. Now, from those, you will be actually extracting these type of information. So, it's not only chunk level, you will be actually looking into the document in a global level also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is very, very important. It means that, forget about RAG, you need to, first of all, define a structure.
Krish NAik: Once you have defined this set of rules that we generally refer to as the ontology set, okay, now then only you can proceed ahead. Can we say each edge will be a metadata? Yes, those things. Now, later on, you can actually use this information, and you can build your own set of schema for the metadata.
Krish NAik: I can say that, yes, later on, like, the filter, with respect to your vector DB, it will be much faster.
Krish NAik: If you actually really want to use some information, because I've seen, like, actually we'll be using a Gravity, but later on, if you want to
Krish NAik: Perform some type of transformation through that, if you want to keep that.
Krish NAik: Now the question comes, notes and edges in this part. Okay, so this is the first set, now we'll move to the second set, which is the attribute schemas. So generally, what is the attribute schema? Now, here you can see the metadata-driven, concept that we have kept it.
Krish NAik: Now, this is where… what we'll be defining. See? Now, this is where you'll be defining relationship.
Krish NAik: It means that, with every set, how it is being connected.
Krish NAik: Now, let me just make it a bit smaller, okay? It actually makes sense.
Krish NAik: Now… hmm… Let me just open…
Krish NAik: What is the name of the file? Okay, I think, yes. In my local, it's there, so directly I will open it.
Krish NAik: Now, see, before looking into the diagram directly, I can suggest you, you can always look into the core, because I feel that it's easier to directly look into the text. Now, can you see here, the document ontology, the financial section? Now, this is the document.
Krish NAik: Now, first of all, I'm defining all my nodes. Can you see? These are nodes. Document, chunk, company, person, metric, event. Now, once I have done, the next thing that comes is edges. What is the purpose of edge?
Krish NAik: Connecting two nodes. Simple term. See, here. Document to chunk. This is part of. Part of is what? The age that I'm talking about.
Krish NAik: Is this part clear? The directly look into the code of Mermaid, or from the Mermaid workflow, in whichever way you understand. The idea is that you get the first step of building a knowledge base, or the knowledge graph.
Krish NAik: then only GraphRag is useful. Okay? Now, once you have done step one, then let's come to step two.
Krish NAik: In step 2, you'll be working with the attribute schemas, okay? So, attribute schemas, it means that, okay, I have defined my nodes and edges. Now the question comes, you really need to attach the schema, because this is the actual thing through which you'll be saving the information in a graph database.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, because the attribute schemas are the most important, because this is where you try to define the rules. But again, once you have built the rules, the next thing is.
Krish NAik: You need to apply the rules on top of your dataset, because
Krish NAik: It's not for one document. You have to maintain the rules for every type of document. So, we'll be building that schema, so that the schema is followed by every set of document that you try to approve.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why the attribute schemas will come. Okay, now for the attribute schemas, so I've kept it, like, you can see here, one is LLM extracted, so defining the properties attached to each node type.
Krish NAik: Okay, now here you can keep, like, okay, now in this schema, for example, the name, the name has to be a string.
Krish NAik: Now, with respect to any extraction, so here you can actually define, okay, now this is my schema, and in this schema, this should be the type of data that is incoming.
Krish NAik: So this is actually another setup rule, or simply, like, the data type rules that you can actually pass it, where you can actually put multiple level of validations.
Krish NAik: For example, whether you are getting the correct information, because I feel that sometimes the NER model might fail. So, this is where you can actually capture that information, and you can add a validation.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody is getting, because this is the part… okay, now, here you have done the extraction, but you need to do the validation also. Through attribute schemas, actually, you can do that validation. So, here are two things, like, you can use an LLM, otherwise you cannot use an LLM also. But I feel…
Krish NAik: If you're working with LLM at every point of time, the cost of the solution highly rises.
Krish NAik: Okay, and generally in GraphRags, if you have a good relationship built, you don't need elements.
Krish NAik: Okay, but again, like, it's totally an option, so this is the part where I feel that
Krish NAik: the validation needs to be done. So, for the validation, if you feel that, yes, you really need to work with LLMs, with respect to the attribute schemas and others, you can, do it. Now, Venkat is asking, please share the link. The link is there in the same one.
Krish NAik: MS, you can ask your answer. Now, Webb, can we say each node will be, okay, already replied to that?
Krish NAik: Fine. Now, what about SLM? SLM, if you can train an SLM for your domain-specific data, even that will be my preference.
Krish NAik: Okay, whatever, really, like, anybody for them, because we really don't need an LLM in this case. I feel that if you have an LLM, but again, training an SLM is a different stuff. I don't want to do the discussion, I want to keep it generic much more, but that will be my priority even.
Krish NAik: Like, at least if I have 500MB of data, probably I will go with a light-based model, having
Krish NAik: 2 billion parameters, and I can train it on within…
Krish NAik: 36 hours, the training will be done, and probably I can do it. It is a better approach, at least.
Krish NAik: Now, didn't follow. We don't need to use the LLM since we need it at the end. No, no, no, no. See, that LLM is different. That is the generation part. I'm not talking about RAG right now, Mudasar.
Krish NAik: I'm only talking about defining this relationship and validating this relationship. Whatever the thing that you have defined in Step 1 needs to be validated. Now, there, the extraction which is done by any type of node or model. Because, see, node and edge.
Krish NAik: I have defined the rules, but later on, this rules for that, if I'm using an NER model. Now, what are the things that has been extracted? You need to do the validation. Now, that validation I'm talking about, that do you want to use that, through using an LLM? I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: I'm not talking about that LLM, which is the output of the rag, okay?
Krish NAik: All right, now, finally, see, once you have done step 1 and Step 2, it means that the document ontology then comes attribute schemas, and finally, the knowledge graph build. Now, this is where, finally, you can build your knowledge graph.
Krish NAik: So, like, any type of documents, so right now, I've taken the example of financial documents and 8K earnings from ACC. Now, this is a famous data set.
Krish NAik: So that's why I've taken an example here. Now comes your document parsing, chunking, dockling, minor, anything that you apply, any type of parsing mechanism. From there, the metadata extraction. Now, you can use an LLM or without an LLM, but you can pass a set of rules here, like what is the document ID, source URI, filing date, exchange.
Krish NAik: Now, these all information can be fetched through an NER-based model also.
Krish NAik: As well as, semantic chunking, if you are trying to apply. Now, this is where your actual document collection works. Now, the question comes where you want to save it. Sometimes, you might save it in a simple SQL, new SQL,
Krish NAik: databases. So that's why I've taken MongoDB, just to give you an example, because GraphDB is also actually a NoSQL database.
Krish NAik: Okay, so don't treat it as separate. It comes under NoSQL only.
Krish NAik: And then comes your main document ontology, because this is where the actual game plays. Like, without this definition, there is no purpose of using graphite. Okay, so if you don't have these rules or the set of rules, can you see here directly the semantic chunking is directly dependent on this set of rules?
Krish NAik: And finally, once you have defined the rules, the next step is the entity resolution. It means that any type of NER model, like, through an LLM, or you are using your own custom NER model, in both the ways, that entity resolution is the first thing.
Krish NAik: Once the NTT resolution is done, then finally comes your main observation, where you actually do the validation. So, now this is the step where you want to look into your answers, if you want to do the validation using an LLM, or through some type of techniques, because here, I feel that it's a better approach if you do the validation by yourself, at least for a subset of documents.
Krish NAik: Because if you have 1,000 documents, not possible, but for at least. Because going forward.
Krish NAik: It becomes, in your initial phase of building any type of custom models, it's a good practice to look into certain sub-stages of that, training data that you will be using.
Krish NAik: Because I cannot build the training data in one shot. From here only, I'll be…
Krish NAik: actually getting my data, that I'll be using it for training. Anything. Or at least to pass some type of golden rules.
Krish NAik: Now, here I'll be looking based on NER. Now, this is the part where you actually do the validation. Now, anything that… because you need to really understand, in the
Krish NAik: Graphite, when you actually look into the dimensions.
Krish NAik: Do you think that with respect to time, the nodes should increase? How many of you feel that the number of nodes in the knowledge graph or the knowledge base should increase with respect to time?
Krish NAik: Yes, please let me.
Krish NAik: But it should be fixed.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, see, now many of you are telling, it is fixed.
Krish NAik: Now, my preference will be, it should be fixed, now the question comes, if it sees something unseen, then again, I need to add it. Now, both answers are correct, but
Krish NAik: Again, the balance. It means that you cannot keep on adding stuff. It should be in some rare conditions.
Krish NAik: It means that, yes, it should be flexible, you can add something, but it's not like adding randomly stuff. It means that at every call, you are adding and making changes to a graph. It's a very, very bad practice.
Krish NAik: If you're doing it very minor updates, if you see that, really, this particular node is important, it means that for that particular setup entity, you are getting many, many requests. It means that more documents are coming, and if you feel that, okay, that node needs to be defined, then only need to add it.
Krish NAik: So don't keep on adding notes. It's a bad practice.
Krish NAik: It means that… One of the
Krish NAik: makes your rules fixed. Yes, you can make it flexible, but again, not every day. You should not change the rules every day. With respect to time, you should make changes to the rules.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm telling you, yes, that it should be flexible, but it's not like that every hour, at every API call, you are changing the graph. It's a very bad practice.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, usually I will say that that balance you need to maintain. You need to actually analyze what type of data is incoming, because for sure, the set of rules that you are defining, it won't be open. So, that's why I always suggest for open domain problems.
Krish NAik: You should not go ahead with GraphRack, where you feel that the customer will upload anything.
Krish NAik: It's a good practice if you're actually working with some enterprise-level stuff, where you feel that, yes.
Krish NAik: Actual relationship that can be defined.
Krish NAik: For example, majorly, like, any type of internal company.
Krish NAik: internal enterprise-based documents where you feel connecting multiple databases, where one SQL table is connected with another SQL table that is connected, there you can actually define relationship. Now, just think about a flat text. Flat text means just you have passed 1,000 pages
Krish NAik: of a simple period. In that case, GraphRag doesn't matter.
Krish NAik: Because you cannot really define that relationship.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why you have to understand that when to use it. It's very, very important. Otherwise, if you don't have any relationship in your document, just think you uploaded a 10-page document, but there is no actual relationship. The set of rules that you have defined, totally, it's different.
Krish NAik: Then, do you think that it is useful to use GraphRag?
Krish NAik: So that's why in open domain, I never suggest. If you have something close domain-specific, where you know that, okay, this is the format of the data that I'll be always getting, there is a certain structure, that's why I've taken financial documents or financial contracts for now.
Krish NAik: In the next, one that I have taken is the social media, because I know there will be a structure, for example, with respect to post. With that post, a lot of things, like sentiment analysis, thread, profile targets, I know multitamel structure will be there, but I can extract that information, and this structure will never change.
Krish NAik: So, wherever you feel that, there is no structure, you cannot define a relationship, please don't go ahead with Maverick.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody's getting, because here, the most important thing is that defining this particular ontology. If you cannot do step one and step two.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you cannot define, or you cannot do this, then the step 3, which is the most important thing, like, building the knowledge graph, because this knowledge graph, you save it in a graph database. So if this is only not correct, then actually the purpose of working with Graph, right, doesn't make sense.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I'm telling that please get it, because this is the most fundamental, and in every research, they will be talking about this.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, the thing that I have told, if you remember, when you
Krish NAik: Actually, try to make changes in a… graph.
Krish NAik: Based on API calls, because I told you, making changes to a graph, it's a bad thing, but yes, with respect to time, you should make it flexible, but not on everyday API calls. It's totally based on the document when you feel that for a certain request.
Krish NAik: You are getting more and more, then you can actually add that node with a relationship.
Krish NAik: Okay? And you can update that. But now the question comes.
Krish NAik: If you're actually making it… if your graph becomes bigger and bigger with respect to time, what will happen?
Krish NAik: Can I say that latency issues will be there?
Krish NAik: Yes or no? Tell me. Latency issues.
Krish NAik: With respect, if your graph is becoming bigger and bigger.
Krish NAik: Always remember that the latency issue will come in, and why it will come? Because of?
Krish NAik: Multi-hop Travelter.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, the… in every graph, there is a traversal technique, and generally, when you are actually going from, one node to one node, that is called as your multi-hop traversal technique, okay? So, for example, here, if I say, okay, now…
Krish NAik: Let's take something, because for that I need an actual graph, then only I can see it.
Krish NAik: Can you have evaluation of the node size structure? Evaluation of node size? No, node size? Now the question comes, when you want to do the evaluation, Venkat?
Krish NAik: Because at every step, you don't want to do it, I think.
Krish NAik: Because the node size that you were telling, yes, you can add validation, but I told you, no, those validations with respect to the node, everything needs to be handled at this attribute schema part.
Krish NAik: I hope you get it, Venkat.
Krish NAik: Because this is the part with respect to where your major entity types and everything that you are actually doing the validation through attribute schemas.
Krish NAik: of the above, the step one, where you actually defined your nodes on that part. I hope you get that one good. Will it increase the cost? Yes, the cost will increase, but really, like.
Krish NAik: I feel that if you have lesser notes, if you have something which is fixed, it's really good.
Krish NAik: GraphRag works when the document follows the same template exactly correct, okay? Now, I do have another paper, because I have added really, because GraphRag is… till now, just remember, GraphRag is a continuous research till now in 2026.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, people are actually doing the research, so it's not, completely done, so I think…
Krish NAik: Okay, now, yes, now this is the other paper that I got, and the same thing which has been written here also, you can go through this.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is a GraphRack benchmark. When should you use it? Like, normal rack versus GraphRack? They're… they have taken a normal one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is also a good paper, you can actually do a rehab, attached it in the motion also, but the same thing that we have discussed about. The evidence extraction, logic extraction, all these things that comes.
Krish NAik: Okay, so node count, edge count, different type of validation that needs to be done.
Krish NAik: So, this is another. So, this paper, I feel that it really gives you a much wider idea that when actually you need graphs in a rack, so it means that when you want to build graph racks.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that 20-30% of the times. Now, what we do, because till now in hybrid search, we have learned that, okay, let's take our BM25, let's take our 10s. Now, people will say that, okay, let's add this also 1.
Krish NAik: But always remember, it comes with a cost. If you want to actually introduce graphs into the system, you need a dedicated graph database. So, for sure, the costing comes.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, it's a good solution. It's just like a fallback. If it doesn't work, okay, let's look into this. If it doesn't work, let's look into this.
Krish NAik: It's really good, but again, the problem with respect to cost.
Krish NAik: So that's why I'm telling, like, now going forward, whenever you think in your mind, what is the hybrid retrieval technique, it means that you have to bring that graph also into the picture. Your sparse, your dens, and your graph, three things. And if you really think about the multi-vector, then four things comes into the picture. I hope everybody get it.
Krish NAik: Because those 3 things already I have taught you, now going forward, whenever somebody is talking about a hybrid retrieval and drag, take this part also.
Krish NAik: The graph retrieval part.
Krish NAik: Okay, now Matthew is asking, please share the link to graphs in RAG.
Krish NAik: Like, which link? Graphs and right? When you say, okay, now this paper are you talking about? This paper is there, I think, in notes, and I've added it, just for you.
Krish NAik: I think in Notion, I have added majorly all the papers that I'm discussing. You can see here.
Krish NAik: one of the papers, just click on this, I think the second paper. Yes, this is the paper, okay?
Krish NAik: Okay, now Mohit is asking, could you please, tell me the reason when we need to use GraphRab when you have an ontology which is defined, Mohit? As simple as that. Because this entire discussion of 30 minutes that I have done, it's for ontology.
Krish NAik: Okay, and really, if you want to check this, I think the ontology paper, where is that? OG? Okay, the actual original
Krish NAik: Reeves, when I say, like, Gangster comes into the art, but yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is… they have an open-based implementation also, and if you really look into… Now, this is the paper one, let me just go into the paper, and really, later on, you can explore this.
Krish NAik: Because the original GraphRad paper gives lesser idea, later on much better paper scheme, which… where I feel that it was better.
Krish NAik: Now, this also, I have attached it in your part. Okay, now if you, really look, and if you really look into this, particular date, you will feel that little bit old, but, finally, like, when… the main idea with respect to Draper Agatha King.
Krish NAik: Okay, because the same paper comes from Microsoft, AJ, okay? And now, if you really
Krish NAik: Look here. So, comparison of the proposed OG rag with an existing RAG solution. Now, the same thing that I have told you, see, the documents will come, now the domain experts will define what is the set of rules that needs to be defined. Yes or no?
Krish NAik: the domain expert guy, he will define, this is the ontology. Now, the ontology grounded hypergraph, it means that your final, that the knowledge graph in step 3 that I have shown.
Krish NAik: Once you have defined that knowledge graph, then the next thing that comes here.
Krish NAik: How many of you get it?
Krish NAik: That's why I told Step 1, define your node, and then define… work with your attribute schemas.
Krish NAik: And then finally, build your knowledge graph. So that's where directly this ontology-grounded hypergraph is actually your knowledge graph that we are referring here.
Krish NAik: Alright, now for everybody, I hope it should be at least clear in high level that
Krish NAik: when we should work with GraphRag. It's not blindly for any type of data, you keep on adding graphs, it's bad. So you need to really take the decision. When you see that, okay, similar type of data, at least, you are getting 30-40% of the times, and generally it's good for
Krish NAik: closed solutions. When you feel that, okay, now this is the setup document, every day that I am getting it, in those cases, I feel it's much better.
Krish NAik: At every point of time, if your document is changing, then working with GraphRag is really a bad practice.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody gets this stuff, okay? And, you can actually look into it. Now, give the GraphRag whitepaper link.
Krish NAik: just searched it. I think that is also from that one.
Krish NAik: You need that tag.
Krish NAik: From local… just wait.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… The graph rack paper, really, like, if you want not this one.
Krish NAik: Because Microsoft has really done the major work with respect to the RapRab archive, now this is the actual paper.
Krish NAik: this paper also, if you want. But I will say…
Krish NAik: Start with the OG paper. The OG paper gives you a better idea.
Krish NAik: Okay, actually, because this graph rack paper has actually not focused on
Krish NAik: The ontology part, and which is really, really important, guys.
Krish NAik: Because without that, relationship and other things that… because here, see, directly, in this paper, they have talked about entities and relationships. Okay, and then, finally, you will be building your knowledge graph. From knowledge graph comes your, graphs communities, in the last class, which I've defined, which was actually your cluster.
Krish NAik: Okay, now… but before reaching to this, you really need to focus on these two things.
Krish NAik: And for these two things, you need the understanding of an ontology. Without that… now, that part is highly missing in this paper, okay? So that's why always remember, start with the OG paper. Once you have the OG paper with you, then come to this. So first, always start that. That gives you a much better
Krish NAik: I can say understanding, like, why GraphRack comes into the picture, and without that structure of ontology, then GraphRack doesn't make any sense.
Krish NAik: Right now, theoretical part, we have discussed a lot. So, from here…
Krish NAik: Okay, we will move a little bit towards our main implementations now. Because today I'll be talking about another database. In the last class, I think, we talked with Neo4J.
Krish NAik: let me take… so you can open your Notion, I have already attached those things, so… Alright, I have this vector graph, like, everybody,
Krish NAik: Please clone this report. 7th March, the first one is a kit. Please clone this one. Then we will try to execute.
Krish NAik: Venkat?
Krish NAik: He's asking, recently I joined the RAC bootcamp, could you please share the notion?
Krish NAik: then cut you a joint, like, we have only one month left in this course. Probably in the next cohort, do shift. In RAG 2.0, I think probably, like, June or July, it will come. DeShift in that bunch.
Krish NAik: Okay. Alright, so… Just glued.
Krish NAik: The OG rag, okay, alright.
Krish NAik: OG rack paper, Satish, all the paper links, I have attached it here only in Notion, no? Go to this graph rag section, and here you have the OG paper, okay, why graph rags, every major paper. Only the base paper I have not added, which is that one. I think in the last class.
Krish NAik: Okay, so can you see here this… the original white paper, whoever asked that, that is already added last class.
Krish NAik: So, from here, you can tick it.
Krish NAik: Because the decision of going ahead with GraphRag, it's really, I feel that
Krish NAik: Yeah, for that little bit understanding with respect to structures and other things which are really required.
Krish NAik: Once you have that overall idea, then actually you can take that particular decision.
Krish NAik: So that's why, today I discussed, because I feel that less people discuss about ontology, okay, rather than everybody start working directly on the knowledge graph. But how to build the knowledge graph? This is very, very important.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the step of building a good knowledge
Krish NAik: Graph, okay, always comes in these three steps. The first two steps, if you actually do it, then move to the third one. So always follow these rules. Okay, so that's why the high-level idea that I have shared
Krish NAik: Alright, so people are asking.
Krish NAik: Sorry to familiarize the content and join now, can you share the GitHub link?
Krish NAik: This GitHub is different, that GitHub is different. Is there any cheat sheet? There is no cheat sheet, I can say.
Krish NAik: Now, see, this is one Thai person, so, like.
Krish NAik: cheat sheet for GraphRag, I cannot directly see that.
Krish NAik: But at least before taking the decision, you can actually go through the paper that Y graphs, why graph racks, okay, and when. I feel that it will give you a lot of answer.
Krish NAik: I'm referring to the Git clone. Okay, now this is the old one. Now, today's one, okay, alright, today's one you are asking.
Krish NAik: This is also attached here, the one that I'll be discussing.
Krish NAik: If you want that, this is a vector graph, right?
Krish NAik: I'm sharing the link. Here, also, I'll be using Neo4J. Later on, I think I have a few use cases with respect to Falco.
Krish NAik: Falcon DPI want to discuss, because that is the fastest GraphRack. It means that that database is only built for one purpose, for building graph racks, that's why. Like, it's faster than any other GraphRack product in the market.
Krish NAik: even, like, Oracle's speeds is very slow. Anything, AWS, wherever, like, AWS and Neptune, that is also very slow. Only the fastest one in the market is Falker. The other one is Memgraph. Okay, if you guys have heard about, that is also a famous one then, or AngoDB is there.
Krish NAik: But everything is slow, so that's why a little bit about Falcon, that will be tough. So, everybody please take a clone, and then please do the setup of your .env, if you really see here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, I have taken a normal database, like the Pinecone one.
Krish NAik: So, the Pinecone Neo4j, as you know that I keep on changing things in every class, so please do set up your .en.
Krish NAik: No, page index later on I'll be discussing. I'll be taking that as an extra class, wherever.
Krish NAik: Okay, because vector less right how to build for that, because I think I'm traveling on Thursday back to Bangalore. Once I'm back to Bangalore, then I have more time, actually. Now I'm in my hometown, I have lesser time to take extra classes also. Okay, so from next week, I think Saturday, Sunday, so next week,
Krish NAik: Wednesday… not Wednesday, Wednesday, on Thursday, I'll be taking an extra class for vector.
Krish NAik: Because those will be small sessions, because it's a paid one, not completely open source, but let's try to get that idea, what they have done it.
Krish NAik: Everybody please do the setup. I think you guys can do the setup by this time in this course.
Krish NAik: Pretty much, we are in the last phase of this code, so I think everybody should be familiar with this setup. Pinecone API, you can get it. You can get the Pinecone host. Host means the URL. Endpoint. Then, these are the local ones, so let me start my new 4J desktop.
Krish NAik: Okay, OpenAI base URL, that is the main one API slash V1 completion V1, that, URL will need to happen.
Krish NAik: Alright, in the last class, I think we have done this stuff.
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: Because, I feel that, next.
Krish NAik: Before starting GraphRag, it's better to at least have a little bit of idea with respect to land graph.
Krish NAik: Because the routing technique is important there.
Krish NAik: I will just delete everything. In the meantime, you guys, please do the setup.
Krish NAik: But I think by this time, everybody should be familiar of doing the setups. Because, again, I've cleaned everything, I'll be creating a new instance, and I will start my work.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me open… I think this means.
Krish NAik: Because this is the notebook that I'll be executing.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this notebook is actually connected with a script, a set of scripts that I have.
Krish NAik: So, if I really show you my env file, just wait.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, my NV file.
Krish NAik: Can you see here?
Krish NAik: the Pinecone API key, the Pinecone host, okay, new 4G, and these type of stuff.
Krish NAik: These are all my local.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just create the local, because locally I don't have one, I will be creating it.
Krish NAik: So take your time, take 5 minutes. Please, guys. Now, Mudassar, I didn't get an answer last time, but, should we consider that MCB approach? No, MCB, it totally depends, like, MCB, when?
Krish NAik: MCP approach means using an MCP, what do you want to do?
Krish NAik: Yes, we haven't discussed Langra up yet.
Krish NAik: I think, tomorrow he stack will be discussing. Then next week, I think Langraf will come after one, because a little bit about the multimodal rack, then I want to focus on the last topic, which will be pretty much Langraf, of course.
Krish NAik: No, Masda is asking using tools like Claude to code, and using entropy.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Clot to gold… I'm using MCP.
Krish NAik: Now, see, when you say MCP, exactly, like, what is in your MCP, that part I want to focus on, like, Magdasar.
Krish NAik: Because cloud-to-code, I got it. Fine, you are using that. But actually, like, how you are defining, like, your MCP server that you have built, what type of calls it is making, I'm much more worried. It means that the rules, you know, your MCP server is doing, like, exactly what type of task.
Krish NAik: If you can give me that idea of the visualization, it becomes much easier for me.
Krish NAik: Amazon Invas is asking, do we need to use the old Pinecone? Yes, you can use your old Pinecone accounts, I have no issues with that.
Krish NAik: Let's assume we have an operation, related documents, like start, application, create file, SOPTC, does GraphTag will give… yes, now see, if you have that related documents, when you say related, Dinesh, then I can say that, yes, you can do that.
Krish NAik: Now, always remember that the SOP that you have, now, that SOP has a certain structure, and it is fixed.
Krish NAik: It means that suddenly, That it doesn't change the entire structure.
Krish NAik: then you can do it, because the core thing, if I feel that, okay, the SOP part. In that SOP, if you feel that, that is somewhere a fixed setup relationship, please go over it.
Krish NAik: Because when I say something is dynamic at every time, if it is dynamic, you will be doing updates. Now, let's take a simple example.
Krish NAik: what happens, really, like, and, like, when the graph rag will fail? Because I told you the easiest example that I can take. Now, if you have any set of documents, so initially, if it is lesser number of documents, let's take 10 documents for now.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you are actually changing your RAG, okay? If you are changing your graph.
Krish NAik: Mainly the knowledge base right now. The notes, it's fine.
Krish NAik: It won't create an impact.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, in the next step, again, when you are at the step of interact documents.
Krish NAik: Now your graph will be messy.
Krish NAik: It means that, okay, your retrieval will work, but I will say that sometimes it will work, and sometimes it won't work.
Krish NAik: Because really, Don, if the graph has become messy, okay, it takes more time for the model to exactly discover the relationship
Krish NAik: Through that multi-hop traversal technique, like node by node, node by node, if it is connected.
Krish NAik: Now, finally, just think about, once you reach that 1000, it means that I can say a complete failure that you have reached.
Krish NAik: Because the structure definition is not there.
Krish NAik: Okay, the vocabulary within that graph explodes.
Krish NAik: As simple as that. And the level of hallucination, just think about 100% hallucination.
Krish NAik: Okay, so always remember that, okay.
Krish NAik: For a small set of documents, it will work. If you don't have an ontology, which is fine. For an 100, it will work, but again, 50-50%. Like, 50%, it won't work, 50% it won't. At a stage when you have 1,000 docs, a complete failure that you will be reaching.
Krish NAik: Traversal will take time for sure.
Krish NAik: even in a set of, properly, I can say, defined relationship, there also it will take. But the rate of hallucination in those cases, when you have an ontology-defined relationship, the rate of hallucinations will be very, very, very low.
Krish NAik: actually, like, there won't be, if it always follow those rules, whatever. But somehow, if you are out of that scope, and if you have not defined an ontology, and you are telling that, okay, randomly, and now that's why I'm telling you this is a very dangerous thing. If you remember, in the last class, when I showed you this part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, here.
Krish NAik: Getting started with, Langshin. Can you,
Krish NAik: Okay, so here I did that part.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this.
Krish NAik: This is a very, very dangerous thing.
Krish NAik: I hope you get it.
Krish NAik: the first notebook that we have discussed in the last class. There, I didn't define anything. Directly, I told LLM, you figure it out.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine, the LLM will figure it out, but now the question comes, the LLM should figure it out, but the LLM should follow a set of rules.
Krish NAik: Now, that thing, I did it in the next one.
Krish NAik: If you remember here, I have, actually defined that part.
Krish NAik: Somewhere I just paid.
Krish NAik: Mmm, alright… Brent.
Krish NAik: Now, based on the document I told you, alright, can you see here that, for my same set of documents, I have, used that rule
Krish NAik: Because in the first one, the LLM graph transformer here, I have kept it blank. It means that the LLM
Krish NAik: Now, I have no idea about the rules. In the next stage, I told that, okay, fine, I'm working with the LLM graph transfer, but at least it should know what are the types of nodes and what are the type of relationship. So that's, like, the step one that I'm following, actually.
Krish NAik: Without this, really, like, it's a very, very bad practice. So always try to maintain this particular step.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, really, I don't remember. I thought I've discussed the second notebook, but you guys can give me an idea, because this is the only change with respect to that notebook.
Krish NAik: You guys can let me know, because I don't remember that. I thought I discussed.
Krish NAik: In the last class. Yes, you guys can let me know in the chat, did I discuss the second notebook?
Krish NAik: If not, then you did not. Okay, fine, then I will discuss it now.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine, fine, fine, fine, fine, fine. I forgot, I thought I discussed, but,
Krish NAik: Fine, let's discuss this, because this is the same replica of the other notebook, but here, the main purpose of ontology, I think we have defined, so we are good to go with this one, okay? Everybody? So let's discuss this notebook, then I will come to that, other part, okay? So, just open, the same one.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Moit is, asking, when do we need to create an ontology, you said? Without ontology, graph… yes, without an ontology, graph rag is not useful, but in the, last, you create graph rag.
Krish NAik: But in the last, last, I could not get it, like… but in the class, you create a graph right? Last class, yes, in the last class, fine. In the last class, I created a graph right. Okay, alright. Yes, you are correct, but here I didn't set. So I'm telling that if you follow this…
Krish NAik: It will work good for 10 documents, 20 documents, 30 documents, 100. But once you try to scale it up, it will be, like, it's something like that, reaching for a 0% to 100% failure. Slowly, slowly, you are taking that step. I hope you are getting. If you try to take this.
Krish NAik: The more the document increases, Because here you don't have any rules, so I will say the…
Krish NAik: Because at the end of the day, what… for your tree, it will become messy, super messy, with respect to time.
Krish NAik: So it will fail. I hope you get that. Mohit.
Krish NAik: More the document increases, the ontology is needed exactly correct.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, your graph rack or your knowledge graph will be very, very messy.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the rate of hallucination will be pretty much 100%, okay? Now, see, now, in the second notebook, now, this is the main thing that I have changed, okay? Now, for this, so let's start executing, because I have already given you the idea here.
Krish NAik: So, let me check, I think.
Krish NAik: I haven't tested it at all.
Krish NAik: Now, Neo4J, okay, so I don't have a Neo4J, so let me just create a…
Krish NAik: dot ENV, just wait.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: Local post, alright.
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me just create a quick database.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is GraphGrag.
Krish NAik: G-R-A-P-H. The name really doesn't matter, because all that matters to me is the URL. And here, what is the password that I've given? The same one that I'll be using, okay? Ragbatch123.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me just wait.
Krish NAik: Oh, where is Raghdad 123… Let me just read it.
Krish NAik: Now, once I have created it, what I will do?
Krish NAik: And in the next step, How many of you remember that plugin setup?
Krish NAik: So once this setup is done, then finally I will move ahead with the execution.
Krish NAik: Okay, yeah, it pops it a bit.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just wait, it will take some time to do the restart.
Krish NAik: So, once, finally, okay, I can see it says in starting phase.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this part is done, so I think I'm good to go with the execution. No, this is the vector one, where is the VS Code, VS code.
Krish NAik: Let me call out for Agnes.
Krish NAik: Respect.
Krish NAik: Now, here I'm passing the PDF directly, so let me just copy it.
Krish NAik: I'll write Jupyter 4040 Mini.
Krish NAik: And just be sure if you are executing the same notebook after one month, because the four old models will be getting duplicated by end of March, okay? So please do change your model after one month, if you're really working with this.
Krish NAik: Fine. Now, the same step that I'm doing right here.
Krish NAik: Because these things are pretty much self-explanatory, I don't feel that I need to explain these things to you anymore.
Krish NAik: I don't have value error, it's not a valid… Or dry Lafranc.
Krish NAik: I don't have… did I delete it that?
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me see that, where is this file?
Krish NAik: I thought I had the file here.
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me… Well, without that particular… Wouldn't open.
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me search.
Krish NAik: I think you guys have that, file.
Krish NAik: I think I have deleted in the last class.
Krish NAik: Please let me know
Krish NAik: Just wait, I will search that file. I think I have it in my downloads folder. I'll just copy-paste that.
Krish NAik: Alright, I got it.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine, I have added it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so 97 chunks.
Krish NAik: Nope.
Krish NAik: Fine, let's, connect it to my new 4G now. These are the same things in the last files that I have discussed, so I'm not, talking about that.
Krish NAik: moderate.
Krish NAik: Now, it's pretty much blank graph right now, so node properties, relationship, and everything will be pretty much blank, okay.
Krish NAik: Now, the next stuff was about the ontology definition that I took.
Krish NAik: Ontology is same as defining the graph relationship with the nodes. Yes, exactly correct. That is the first step. Ontology means the set of rules that you are defining. And the rules definition means nodes
Krish NAik: With that, relationship.
Krish NAik: Okay, that is the meaning of ontology.
Krish NAik: Now, this is where I am defining, okay? So, what are the node type that needs to be allowed? Now, see, this is one sample schema that I have kept it, so that it becomes much easier, because in the last notebook, I have just executed this LLM graph transformer.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I have not passed any type of node definition or allowed relationship here. See? Now, if you really look into this person organization concept here, this is just an example, and if you open this Markdown file, can you see here? This is actually the same set that I'm doing it here.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so if I open it in my long previous, okay, because this is actually the same thing here that I've defined, and the node and the edges.
Krish NAik: If you really see part of reference… now, this is the same thing here. Allowed relationship, like, related to works at, mentions, contains, those things that comes.
Krish NAik: So here, I'm actually defining that.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, here, one property is there, allow strict mode is equal to false.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you feel that, if you want to do, because allow extraction outside the schema. If you really want to feel that, because I feel that you should always leave it as false.
Krish NAik: Because you can give the flexibility, but if you don't want to give the flexibility, then it's fine. Okay, now this is the same thing for my weather document. I know that in that weather document, like, concept is there, phenomenon is there, substance is there, process, technology, ecosystem. Now, see, now this decision, who will take the
Krish NAik: Who will take this decision?
Krish NAik: In the OG paper, it was told, the domain expert will take.
Krish NAik: No, no, Jatin, the user, why the user? The domain expert will come, no? The subject matter expert. He will know that, okay, for this set of documents, these are the actual notes that needs to be taken.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, you have to, also understand that thing. Here, can you see here that for every key, there are certain values?
Krish NAik: Now, this is also important, because when you are actually working, for example, if I say
Krish NAik: a short form and a full form. But actually, the representation is the same.
Krish NAik: For example, if I say, like, IBM,
Krish NAik: And if somebody says the full form of IBM, can I say that the meaning should be same?
Krish NAik: So you should have that, set of rules, like key and value pair.
Krish NAik: That if you are talking about that particular word, so what are the probable synonyms?
Krish NAik: In one sec.
Krish NAik: It is not exactly the synonyms, I mean that similar words that you feel that, which you can actually group under the same thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so always try to follow these rules, and in that way, I feel that the graph becomes better, your knowledge graph will perform much better.
Krish NAik: Now, one of the simplest example of GraphRag
Krish NAik: Like, any type, like, the government is right now working, the Indian government. There is something called as Nat Grid. Anybody ever heard about NAT grid?
Krish NAik: Indian government is working on that. For example, like, in US, Palantir is working, very similar to ADHAR technology, again, their graphs are widely used.
Krish NAik: The National Grid, yes. The National Grid, net grid, where it'll actually… getting connected with everything. Your financial documents, your bank statements, your pass.
Krish NAik: Everything, your business data, everything.
Krish NAik: Through that, like, it'll become much easier to get, and that information will be used by security agencies.
Krish NAik: Pretty much a tracking-based system, in simple terms, but yes, the government can quickly gather data about anyone.
Krish NAik: the National Intelligence Correct. The Indian government is working on very similar technology in the US, like Palantir. They have also done that, thing. Now they are actually developing very similar to ADA, but they're also graph-based representation. I'm not talking about graph rack, but pretty much the use of graphs.
Krish NAik: Scalable, yes, but you know that there will be a set of rules. If there is a set of rules, really, you can follow that thing.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm telling you. Scalability, yes, it is possible. There won't be any type of problems, but again, the rules, they are not changing the rules. With respect to time, I know the rules will be fixed, even after 5 years, 10.
Krish NAik: So in those cases, highly scalable stuff. Okay, but again, if you don't have the rules, not scalable. As simple as that.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's talk about these things.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here I have allowed, these are the nodes, and these are the relationships that needs to be defined. So, concept phenomena, so these…
Krish NAik: particular decision needs to be taken by a domain expert. Here, I'm telling, okay, the node properties, with respect to, like, description and source, these are the default properties, but going forward, you can add more and more properties. So, when I'm talking about these node properties and relationship properties, guys.
Krish NAik: So now, attribute schema that I have defined. Now, there I can… there I have given more examples, but for now, I've just kept it very, very, very short. Only description and source, and in the node, property is the relation, but here you can add more and more things.
Krish NAik: semantically, similarly nodes in ontology, can you please expect an, approach of how we can define semantically similar node or relationship? Semantically, when you are telling, it means that
Krish NAik: How you're defining that semantic? It means that, are you defining some properties of a node with the other node, using…
Krish NAik: Cosine similarity?
Krish NAik: Wherever. Because, see, right now, we are not working with vector databases.
Krish NAik: I'm working with graph databases.
Krish NAik: So, semantic, when you use the term semantics, exactly.
Krish NAik: What is the meaning? Because when anybody… if you use the term semantic, it means that some type of
Krish NAik: Distance calculation, and pretty much it's a cosine similarity.
Krish NAik: Okay, for that synonyms, okay, for that synonyms, you need to build your own key-value store.
Krish NAik: anyone.
Krish NAik: See, Madhasar, cosine dot, those things will come when I say much more about vector.
Krish NAik: Okay, but if you actually, think about that semantic meaning, you have to use one set of rules. So, for example, just…
Krish NAik: Let's take one simple example, let me just open the notes and show you, because again, in code, if I try to write it, I don't want to change that code here. Just wait, where is my iPad, iPad, iPad, iPad do I have?
Krish NAik: Mmm, just food.
Krish NAik: Has it started? Already, yeah, it started, fine.
Krish NAik: College.
Krish NAik: So, right here, if I say that, okay, now… now, this is actually a good question which Beva was asked. Okay, now, like, if you have just the synonyms, this example that I told, for example, IBM.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, if you have… now, how to identify that? So, for that, you need to create some type of registry, so let's take, like, in…
Krish NAik: entity.
Krish NAik: You're registered.
Krish NAik: If you have this, the in-ear will be, because the name-entity relationship model, if you are using separately, okay, it will become much more robust. So, for example, let's take one valve.
Krish NAik: Now, inside my entities, Okay, so what I will do…
Krish NAik: Yeah, so let's take my entity as my main… Okay.
Krish NAik: Inside that, if I say, for example, let's take IBM.
Krish NAik: Now, this IBM should be mapping to multiple other keywords, which will mean. For example, if I say.
Krish NAik: I. BM Corp.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Now, this IBM co-op can be, like, international business machines, somebody might call it, so I'm not writing, I'm just writing IBM full form for now.
Krish NAik: You have to build this tab by yourself, so that your NER performs better. If you're actually building these things, I can say it will be better. Similarly now, this is for IBM that I told, multiple other things that you can add in.
Krish NAik: What other things? Sometimes IPM is also referred as, like, the big blue, okay, in that way. Now, for example, person, if I say, let's take one person, like, Microsoft, like, let's take Satanandala, okay? Now, that guy, if you say… so, for example, if I take Paul here only, let's take Paul.
Krish NAik: So here, okay, now my full name will come.
Krish NAik: Okay? Yeah.
Krish NAik: Now, only my one name that might come. So, in that way, you have to create all the synonyms here.
Krish NAik: In this way. It means that these things refer to the same thing which is actually Paul.
Krish NAik: How many of you are getting it? It means that you have to create your own registry of entities for that. I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: Okay, you are Meetesh only. Fine, fine, fine. Okay, alright. I hope you get it now.
Krish NAik: This is NER stuff, it means optimizing your NER pipeline. I'm not talking about graphs right now, but actually, for your better entity recognition, you need these things. This is followed in any type of named entity recognition task, so those things that needs to be managed here.
Krish NAik: But yes, with respect to time now, this key and value set should be increased, it means that.
Krish NAik: See, you can ask the LLM to do it, sir, but that's why, when you are working with a set of rules.
Krish NAik: Everything cannot be dynamic. That's why… okay, so doing it manually would be a pain, I can, but you can actually add an
Krish NAik: evaluation stuff, because I feel that doing changes, it means, like, once a month or twice a month, do it, or once a week. So you have to actually sit and analyze the stuff.
Krish NAik: So, generally, I suggest for open domain, it becomes a very hard problem.
Krish NAik: For closed domain, enterprise-specific, I feel that it's a better way. So, graph rack, I never suggest for, like, open-ended problems or open domain.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now, this is just an example, just to show you.
Krish NAik: Now, see, now, now, if you have this, now, even I can ask the LLM. So, if I ask the LLM to do this.
Krish NAik: Can I say that you can use something like a prompt? Like, I can say that you are an NER expert or an NTT extractor expert, something like that. You may only extract entities from these types.
Krish NAik: And then you pass the set of rules there.
Krish NAik: Okay, and even you can pass that, okay, if this is the piece of text, the written type, because, see, using prompts.
Krish NAik: You can define it, okay?
Krish NAik: This is my input.
Krish NAik: through a placeholder. And what is the output type?
Krish NAik: Here you can say that the return type
Krish NAik: Because you need to follow the rules according to your graph right. So I will say that, okay? So let's take something like this is my entity 1, okay? This is my entity 2 based output, entity 3 based output, entity 4 waste output. This is a structure that I'll be following.
Krish NAik: Okay, and here I will simply say that do not create new entities, which is totally out of the scope, which… okay, so simply, like, I've been manually playing with the prompter. So I'm just giving a rough idea, like, how to do this stuff.
Krish NAik: Alright, I will stop sharing, let's get back to our practicality now. So, I think here it is.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is a set of modes, and that's why I've defined here.
Krish NAik: Okay, now here, allowed relationship that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Now, see, two things. The first piece of code, which I have kept it here. Now, this is without async, okay, but this is async. Now, why I've taken these two examples? This will take a very, very long time.
Krish NAik: very, very long time is really, like, if you want to do the testing, right now, you can just comment this, and you can actually move ahead with this. Okay, you will understand what is the speed here. The speed is really, very slow. Okay, so I've moved from sync to async here.
Krish NAik: Now, why? Because here, first of all, on every type of chunk, it will be doing that. Okay, so that's why the speed, because the NKT recognition on top of your entire chunk.
Krish NAik: It will take time.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I've applied an async here. So, but this is the, simple, synchronous…
Krish NAik: operation, and this is the same thing with… so here you can see, I've used that Nest asyncure package, and through that, I'm updating.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, tell which part I have done the execution, okay, I have not executed this piece of code. Let me do the execution.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: So, this is the node definitions that I have done with the node relationship. Now, let me do this. Now, this will take time, guys. Even it's not, like, super fast.
Krish NAik: Because we are close to 97 chunks, in each chunk, it will go, it will look, so yes, the process is… because I am using LLMs to do that. So, for sure, for every API call that you make.
Krish NAik: Now, the idea is that
Krish NAik: going forward, you should actually replace this stuff, okay? At every point of time, you don't need this LLM graphs transformers. If the documents are dynamic, in low scale, for 5-10 documents, do it.
Krish NAik: But don't follow this same rule for your 1000 set of documents. The solution will become much more costly, but through a prompt example that I showed, where you can control that, do not
Krish NAik: add any more entities or something like that. Always follow these rules that you can manually add.
Krish NAik: Okay, some food.
Krish NAik: And if you actually, like, if you can, you can comment the complete async part, and if you just try to execute with Synchronous, it will take close to 10 to 15 minutes, at least.
Krish NAik: Can we do NER instead of LR? Yes, that is the idea, MS.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm telling, no, in-ear is the… see, right here, I've defined everything, and I'm telling the LLM to do it. But in actual scenarios, you will be using the in-ear.
Krish NAik: Name entity recognition models.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think it's done.
Krish NAik: Let's look into all the graph. So, 97 chunks for that, the all graph documents that I have.
Krish NAik: Now, I'm just printing out, 5 of those nodes and relationships. So, here you can see, based on type, concept, type substance, type process, okay, and these things can be validated. Concept.
Krish NAik: substance, process, all things will come here. Now, based on relationship, causes, contributes, impact, epics.
Krish NAik: Some things will be there with respect to your relationship also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so ID, like, human activities, fossil fuels, deforestations…
Krish NAik: Okay, majorly, and here the type related to, contributed to all those type of, node relationships that are being shown here.
Krish NAik: Now, Chetzan is asking, is it a good idea to create a graph rack based on business rules?
Krish NAik: Do you think that they will be static, and not at every point of time? They… if they are dynamic at every…
Krish NAik: time instance, if I think.
Krish NAik: Okay, then it's a bad practice, if it's a dynamic stuff. If it's static, if you feel that, yes, going forward also, in future, at least think from next 3 months to 6 months, if you feel that chicken, those rules won't be changing.
Krish NAik: Then I will… if it's static, yes, you can use. If it's dynamic at every point of time, if these things are changing, then it becomes very much.
Krish NAik: Yes, people are using industry, that's why I've given you an example.
Krish NAik: For example, like, Palantir is there, Aadhaar, these are pretty much common stuff. University curriculum, can you create an ontology? Yes. Because there, the, syllabus doesn't change, like, at every few things, but the core modules remain the same. Probably some changes can be there with respect to the subgraph part, but it is fine.
Krish NAik: But your actual, I can say, things that will be there. With respect to university syllabus, you can do it. Because I know the university syllabus doesn't change this every day.
Krish NAik: Probably after one year. So, after 1 year, I know that I can make some changes here. I hope you get that, Arun.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, Abhishek, NER can find the entity and the relationship, but, how will you be able to connect entity and relationship? By using an NER model?
Krish NAik: Any type, you can use Spacey NER.
Krish NAik: Okay, or any type of,
Krish NAik: encoder trained model, Abhishek. Any type, encoder.
Krish NAik: Okay? Like, bird-based, NER models are also there. If you want, you can use decoder-based also.
Krish NAik: Okay, but, like, NER, I prefer much more to work with, like, modern bot or something like that. You will get a lot of NER models out there in the market, and for, simple, if you don't want to do anything, directly start working with spaCy NER, the easiest integration that you can do.
Krish NAik: Okay, and it's used in industries, PC and EM.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, the next step is saving this particular information in our, new 4G. So here, graph.graph add documents. Here, I'm passing all graph doc. So, this is where I'm passing, in simple terms, all the chunks.
Krish NAik: Okay, now these are all because 97, so that's why all that graph information. Base entity level is equal to true, so here, I will be adding this, like, underscore, underscore entity. Now, this is a tag which is very specific to NeoFortune.
Krish NAik: And include source is equal to true. Now, this is the actual node, like, from where you are getting the core information. Like, this chunk is part of, like, contains it or mentioned in this document.
Krish NAik: Very similar tag that you were creating. So, this through which you will be actually getting this. So, this is an by default, edge which will be created. You don't have to add any rule for this one.
Krish NAik: Now, after adding this, so let's refresh the schema, and then we'll perform the query. Okay, now here I have passed some sample query. So, when this is added, we will refresh. Now, you have to understand, before making the query, in Neo4J, every time you have to refresh the schema.
Krish NAik: Okay? Or basically update the schema as per the new document ingestion which has been taken place.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this will take some time, so let's wait.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, based on the document, so here, some properties. Okay, so, alright, the refresh schema part is done. Now, here, the graph query, so here, see, creating full text index immediately after loading, so right here.
Krish NAik: So, now, what will be the output, in simple terms? So, what… what does this, first of all, telling me?
Krish NAik: So what is this? In the last class, I have shown you. What is this called? Quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me in the chat, what is this guy's… After query, in… 3-3 adults.
Krish NAik: Okay? Shut up, correct. It's a cipher query language. I hope everybody remembers that.
Krish NAik: And not pure English.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, okay, fine. Now, this is the query that I am passing. Okay. Now, here, graph stored in new version, or this is the actual print statement that you are getting here.
Krish NAik: Okay. After that, full-time text, okay, now the updated schema, graph.schema. Now, this is the schema which is being printed. Print, you can see graph.schema, so this is the actual schema, like ID, text, file path, creator, mod date, keywords, trapped, authors, okay, so some things, total pages, title, creation date.
Krish NAik: Ecosystem, so the total number of nodes.
Krish NAik: 1104 with the number of relationship, which is close to 2493.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, pretty much. And now, if you really look into, with respect to… can you see here, every time they are actually maintaining substance, process, contribute to, you know, these are the set of rules that already has been defined by me.
Krish NAik: And it's just following, node to note. Can you see process and technology, process and substance, process and look? So please scroll down and look into that entire thing.
Krish NAik: But I feel that, see, here… can you see here, the number of nodes and the relationships are quite high? Can I say this, yes or no? Because from here, another thing that I want to make an inference. Whenever you are working with graphite, please use higher
Krish NAik: A chunk life.
Krish NAik: This is important.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can use something like 3,000, 2000. This is very, very specific to GraphRag rule.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, in other cases, I don't suggest to go with such high numbers, but I feel that you should actually look, because 97 chunks for a single document.
Krish NAik: Yes, even if you see that with generic chunking strategies like semantic chunking. On sort of any random document, semantic chunking also gives you very high output.
Krish NAik: But on top of the default semantic chunking, you should add a certain type of condition at the minimum size and the max size. Through that, you can control. Here, also, a very similar strategy. You should actually work with higher chunk sizes.
Krish NAik: Okay? So guys, this is one important thing. Just keep in your mind that going forward, try to use bigger.
Krish NAik: All right, and the minimum chunk size also, that you can keep it towards the higher side, close to 700, 750. Because really, like, I feel that for 97 nodes, fine, but these numbers are towards the higher side.
Krish NAik: All right, now I think, with respect to my
Krish NAik: Next part, see, till now, everything that I have done, this entire thing, which is pretty much big right now, as you can see, I'm… it's taking a lot of time to scroll down also.
Krish NAik: But, my cool things have been inserted into the graph, and really, if I show you the graph, can you visualize the graph? Yes or no? Explore. Connect to an instance. Connect.
Krish NAik: Let's connect, okay? And it will take some time. Show me a graph. Can you see here? Concept, document, ecosystem, location, organization, process, all the things that are shown right now. And based on the entities, if you really look into…
Krish NAik: Okay, so burning fossil fuels, okay, a high-level description with respect to activities that have intensified the natural greenhouse. Can you see your mentions related to everything?
Krish NAik: Because at the end of that, you need to visualize. So this is actually how the graph will look like.
Krish NAik: You guys, please do have a check on this one, because the visualization part is important.
Krish NAik: Now, I'm showing you for one, for other things also you can actually look into.
Krish NAik: With respect to technologies.
Krish NAik: Now, just think, I have just passed a single PDF, and this is the size of the graph.
Krish NAik: I hope you get it when you have the
Krish NAik: 1,000 documents, then what will be the size of the graph?
Krish NAik: Because multiple similar clusters will be formed.
Krish NAik: For one, you can understand, yes, this is how the structure…
Krish NAik: But again, just think about if you have, like, one lakh document, then what will be the structure?
Krish NAik: graph traversal becomes an issue, but again, the latency will increase, but I know the accuracy will be there if you follow those ontology rules. If you go outside that, it becomes a problem.
Krish NAik: So, if you follow the rules always, lesser hallucination, everything will be correct.
Krish NAik: But if you don't follow the rules.
Krish NAik: Again, waste of time. Okay, yes, there will be many, many clusters, that's why.
Krish NAik: Holt.
Krish NAik: So please, I will look into that. And now, really, like, I want, you guys to test it with different, chunk sizes also. Because in my case, I passed a lower one, okay, but try to play with something, a bigger one.
Krish NAik: So here, later on, like, after this, please play with this, param.
Krish NAik: Yeah, okay, so make it, like, close to, like, 3072.
Krish NAik: Okay, and use here around, like, 20%, so make it, like, 600 or something like that, and then see what happens. Little bit the graph will be little bit smaller also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please do play out with these type of things.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let's check. I'm not executed the notebook, so just wait.
Krish NAik: Then we'll be going ahead for a clip
Krish NAik: Okay, now coming, to this, creating a hybrid vector index on Neo 4G.
Krish NAik: Alright, so here…
Krish NAik: Langshan Neo 4J, Langshan OpenAI. Okay, now, see, can you see here this new 4J vector? So, I think around 2024, the new 4J, later on they upgraded their,
Krish NAik: Actual graph database to support vectors also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so previously, the support was not there. In 2024,
Krish NAik: After, graph databases become popular, Neo4j gave the support.
Krish NAik: Now, here what happens in one shot, everything that you can actually save it. Now, in… based on every node also, you can save it. So now, this is very, very specific only to Neo4j. If you change the database again, these things will change.
Krish NAik: So, I'm repeating, now this is highly dependent on the package of Neo4J. So, NeoForge vector, you can see, and in this particular NeoForge vector from existing graph, it means that the graph already I have created. I know the graph is already available to me. So, from there, first of all, the embeddings.
Krish NAik: the OpenAI embedding initialization that I have done it, okay, which is passed here. Then comes search type hybrid. So here, automatically, your vector plus keyword, that implementation is done. So, I will say that this is through the direct package, otherwise you have to do everything manually.
Krish NAik: If you're working with some other databases.
Krish NAik: Alrighty. Now, here, what will be the mode label that I have passed? So, this is the information which will be embedded with the existing graph in the vector database of new version. Okay, now that you cannot actually visualize.
Krish NAik: Only the graph database in Neo4J that the visualization can be done. So here, I'm telling the default node level, keep it document.
Krish NAik: Text note properties. Now, this is the default text. It means that the default, property, it's just like the attribute within the graph. Like, document under that text, which will be coming into the picture.
Krish NAik: Now, the original piece of text within that chunk, so just think about, you have 10 chunks. In that chunk, you have the original text. That will come under this text, and then the embedding. Embedding means the number. The original embedding numbers, that will come under 2.
Krish NAik: Now, you need to create, because in a Neo 4G also, whenever you are saving any embeddings, it needs to be saved inside an index.
Krish NAik: or else… they don't call it as a collection. The same thing, index. Pinecone also uses the term index. So sometimes we call it collection, sometimes we call it index. So, here I'm giving the name vector underscore index. It means that using this vector underscore index, I can make any type of
Krish NAik: What?
Krish NAik: Distance call, like, cosine similarity and everything through this index name that can be performed.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, inside this particular index, I'm, passing, like, what will be the index name, the PDF keyword index that I have passed, then comes the new 4J credentials, URI username, and password, okay?
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is the part where actually I'm inserting my data.
Krish NAik: Okay, and what data? The actual vector database data. This is not related to the graph, but from the graph, I am actually doing it.
Krish NAik: Because this information has already been processed in my main graph, so from the graph directly, I'm making it, so that that hybrid implementation that I can do, it means that your, keyword sparse… okay, it means that keyword or sparse is exactly the same. Then comes your dens, so your vector search.
Krish NAik: sparse search with that, your graph search. Three things.
Krish NAik: Alright, now coming to your graph retriever, because here I have done the…
Krish NAik: embedding ingestion part. I have added the embeddings to the vector database. And what is the vector database here?
Krish NAik: What is the vector database that I am using here right now? Quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: What is the vector database that I am using it here? Everybody is clear I'm not using any third party, it's Neo4j, okay? And when the update for vector database came, Neo4J in 2024 end. Like, around December only, the update came.
Krish NAik: Yeah, and I feel that Microsoft team might have done it, or asked for that. Because once GraphRank becomes popular, the initial research, they have added the vector part also. Now, once the support came from here, I have that added benefit of using the graph, as well as my own vector, DB operations.
Krish NAik: Now, coming to our graph retriever. Okay, now this retriever, from where I'm initializing it, C.
Krish NAik: Guys, this is a custom class that I have created. So, Neo4j, Neo4J Grab, my Dave Retriever.
Krish NAik: Now, what is my base retriever?
Krish NAik: What is my base retriever? Quickly tell me in line.
Krish NAik: Whenever I want to create my own custom retriever, I can inherit the properties of the base retriever. So, like, pretty much like Python tick-based model, if you remember.
Krish NAik: VectorDB1, Neo4j, correct. The interface class, exactly correct.
Krish NAik: Now, I'm inheriting the properties, then I'm telling, okay, what is the graph, the new 4J graph. Now, this initialization I have done on the top, then comes what is my LLM selection, number of hops.
Krish NAik: Now, see, here I am telling… tell how much depth you want to go.
Krish NAik: Now, this is also a parameter for your traversal. So, multi-hop, I told you, like, from one node to one node, it's hop 1. Now, from second node to third node, it is hop 2.
Krish NAik: 3rd note to fourth note, hop 3. I hope everybody understands the meaning of hop.
Krish NAik: HOP.
Krish NAik: There are different concepts, like, sometimes, and you might have heard about the concept of multi-hop reasoning.
Krish NAik: Which is used widely in deep-sea-based models.
Krish NAik: That is different, actually.
Krish NAik: Okay, but… and this is different.
Krish NAik: Okay, so don't get confused, this is a traversal technique, okay? So, I hope everybody gets it.
Krish NAik: multi-hop traversal.
Krish NAik: don't confuse it with multi-hop reasoning, okay? Both the things are different.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, whenever you are actually working with, if you remember, you need to invoke your retriever. In that retriever, the default, function, I can say, which is the get relevant documents. Now, this particular strategy
Krish NAik: We have been following from Langchain, the older version.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I don't know how many of you are getting updated at the Langchen Hub
Krish NAik: Entire package has been updated. A lot of wrappers and other things. Anybody saw it in the LinkedIn?
Krish NAik: From LanChain 0 to LanChain 1, now the new version of LanChain, which has came.
Krish NAik: A lot of changes with respect to the core code, heard about it.
Krish NAik: Yes, because he has the core package. That's why, I don't know, a lot of people were using that, Pokemon in, that part, like, Stage 1, Stage 2, Stage 3, how it got a god.
Krish NAik: I think, finally, In three stages of planning.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now, so this is my get relevant document where I am passing, so extract the key entities, like people, organization, concept, technologies, from this portion as a JSONC. Now, this list that I am passing here, can you see here? Now, what you should add it here?
Krish NAik: Please tell me.
Krish NAik: See?
Krish NAik: That's why I'm telling.
Krish NAik: Here, I have told, say, people, organization, on this part, I have commented it. So, actually, you should be passing something like this, concept, phenomena, substance, process, technology.
Krish NAik: That's why I have actually not fixed this.
Krish NAik: Okay, now you need to actually do this. So, TPL organization concept technologies, this only be your actual prompt, because this is the default one, which I have commented. So, I want you guys to do the change by yourself.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first of all, try with the default one, and then you can actually do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… I hope everybody understands what is the mistake that I have added in the cell.
Krish NAik: And I want you guys to update that.
Krish NAik: PayPal organization concept and technologies to, according to your own setup nodes.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright,
Krish NAik: The response, a JSON list only that we have passed, which is the return type of the fixed nodes. Then, this is the invoke style.invoke, which got updated in Langchen1 as compared to 0.x.
Krish NAik: So, through invoke, I'll be actually invoking that particular get relevant function. Okay, for entity and entities, limit to maximum the return type will be top 5 entities. Okay, now when you look here.
Krish NAik: Now, this is what?
Krish NAik: This is a cipher query language only, that's why I've kept it within the cipher part.
Krish NAik: Through which you can actually get and you can make your call.
Krish NAik: Okay, now things will change here. Can you see here the hops?
Krish NAik: Here, I'm telling node-to-node traversal how many times that you can do maximum.
Krish NAik: So here, according to the parameter here, I have kept it integral to 2, so 2 depth level, or if you want to go much more.
Krish NAik: Because I don't feel that, yeah, like, you should traverse tail end. Till end is a bad practice. Like…
Krish NAik: the latency will be very, very high at every point of time if you go till the last move. So always try to do the restriction here also.
Krish NAik: Alright, now once I have defined till what level of traversal that needs to be done, then finally from this, once I have the mean cipher, okay, now that I'll be performing the query.
Krish NAik: based on the entities which will be extracted through our element. So, that's the entire thing that I have kept it here. Okay, and finally, my main retrieval
Krish NAik: From where I'll be getting that, otherwise simply the exception that I have added it here.
Krish NAik: Now, see, this result is a blank one. At every point of time, I'll be appending all the information with respect to page content, metadata, and everything.
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally comes your LLM generator and your graph retriever objects, which we have already defined it.
Krish NAik: So let me just express it.
Krish NAik: Now, see guys, now this is a line graph workflow. Why I prefer Langraph workflow?
Krish NAik: Because still no, I've not taught you language, but you have to understand that if you… if I use plain language, then it is
Krish NAik: The concept of stateful and stateless.
Krish NAik: live there.
Krish NAik: Whenever you are working, if you feel that I want some type of memory or something.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's why I've taken Langaraf here, because going forward, you guys will be coming, so probably, like, next week or after that, we'll be starting with Langrav, so a little bit, because my main purpose
Krish NAik: Was to create some type of ensemble retriever.
Krish NAik: Okay, so then I need routing, because here are two retrievers, but I need a routing. For that, I have taken Langra app. Okay, so don't be confused.
Krish NAik: Now, here, I have created an ensemble retriever manually by doing the implementation. How many of you get this part?
Krish NAik: Ensemble Retriever. I have taught you in Llama in Death, I remember, but in Langchen, the same thing I am showing you.
Krish NAik: The same thing where we have talked. Can anybody tell me?
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me, guys, because this part I want…
Krish NAik: Ensemble Retriever, where I have taught.
Krish NAik: Where I have taught ensemble Retriever previously to you guys.
Krish NAik: In the hybrid search class, where I had a retriever for my sparse, where I had a retriever for my dens. Now, both of these things.
Krish NAik: How many? Okay, you guys remember? Good. Okay, now the same thing, because that time, I think I have taken Llama. This time, pure land chain, okay? So here, my custom, and here, can you see, I've given an vintage?
Krish NAik: weightage I have given. To the graph retrieval, I've given more weightage as compared to the vector retriever here.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, see, this is a landgraph state modeling with conditional routing. Now, see, this part, really, like, my main focus was that, to create the routing logic, and for that, I have kept Langgraph here, guys.
Krish NAik: And really, like, if you're not comfortable, because till now I've not taught Langraf, but simply the main purpose of this particular big cell that I have is to find out the route.
Krish NAik: It means that whether it should go to that, vector, whether it should go to the graph. So that particular routing technique, okay, so where it should go, so for that, I have used language. I'm not going to discuss the code, and I'll be teaching you Langrav, at that particular point of time, I will explain.
Krish NAik: break later on, let me complete the notebook, then only send Cloud Go for a break.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I do have a lot of plates.
Krish NAik: Alright, so here, if you look into, for now, just try to analyze it. Don't… you don't have to go into depth, because
Krish NAik: Again, later on, I will be discussing when Langraph I have taught you, but right now, just get to the syntactical things in a line graph. Whenever we are working, we define a state. Within that state, then comes your classification of the query. So, whenever user will ask any type of query.
Krish NAik: Okay, for that, like, where it should go. A simple vector, or to the complex one. So that particular routing logic, where I have kept it. So, classify this query into one category. A simple category, which is a direct fact lookup.
Krish NAik: Then, one is the relational ask about relationship connection, how X relates to Y, and then comes the complex, which is the multi-org. Now, complex is actually the graph one.
Krish NAik: Okay, category, the final output will be one word only, whether it's simple relation and complex, based on that, the written type of this particular function. Then comes your vector retrieval node, then comes your graph retrieval node, so here you will be invoking your vector search. Here, graph search. Okay.
Krish NAik: And then comes your hybrid retrieval, so both those things that you have defined needs to be passed inside this particular function, and finally comes generate your answer, where you'll be calling this hybrid retrieval node, as simple as that.
Krish NAik: Okay, and from there, you'll be getting your final, I can say, general. So, all these things, you need to wrap it up, and in a single place, you'll be making the call, okay? So, what is the purpose of Langrav here? It's only that routing part. How many of you get it?
Krish NAik: Because this entire thing, I'm controlling it through Langraph. Langraph is used for orchestration, so you can simply say that in this particular example I have taken. So, don't worry, I have not taught you language graph, but people I know
Krish NAik: few people know Langra, so I hope at least you can get it, okay? So simply skip this, because my main purpose was that routing logic, so for that, I have added. In Langchain, what happens at every point of time, in every execution.
Krish NAik: If my application is stateless, because for, graphite solutions, it's always better to make your application stateful, rather than stateless. So, I have introduced here Langraph.
Krish NAik: Alright, so similarly, now, all these nodes are related to Langraph, nothing to worry about. Let me just pass it here.
Krish NAik: Alright, now I'll be… let's try to do some type of invoking, and based on that, I'll be asking some type of question.
Krish NAik: All right, now this is the main function. Through this function, I'll be passing, and I have kept a few questions here, like, what are hydrogen cell fuels, what are the impact of climate change, and what is argoforestry, okay? So, three things.
Krish NAik: Now, see, this is where I'm simply making a quotient to the Potion to what?
Krish NAik: to my original document that I have passed here. I know in that document there will be something with respect to hydrogen cell phones, okay? Now, here, this is the first question that I have asked. And you see here, first of all, I'm deciding this routing, where it should go, simple.
Krish NAik: Simple, and from here, I'm getting it.
Krish NAik: Now, what are the impacts of climate change? Now, here, for understanding the impacts, you need to really understand an overall level of the document. So, that's why graph, complex, fast selected.
Krish NAik: Not directly that we have brought up now here, extreme weather events, rising temperatures, changing seasons.
Krish NAik: I will say that this particular response will be much better as compared to your normal vector search results, guys.
Krish NAik: You can always do the comparison from here.
Krish NAik: Okay, I always feel that this will be much better.
Krish NAik: Now,
Krish NAik: Okay, now what is argoforestry? Now, I think in the document there was a direct section with respect to Argo forestry, that's a simple one. Because this is much a high-level question.
Krish NAik: And for that high-level question, I can say that the response that I've got is much better as compared to my direct vector search. You can actually do the testing, because the same document we have used multiple times.
Krish NAik: And if you really analyze your previous, responses from, like, what are the impacts of climate, I will say this is one of the best responses till now, in this course for the document that we have done it.
Krish NAik: Because if you guys have analyzed your previous results.
Krish NAik: I will say that this is far better, because a lot of things have been brought.
Krish NAik: So, please, get it, because that's why I want to… wanted to actually discuss this example.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: How many of you feel that? Because, for that, at least you have to remember. That's why I'm using the same document everywhere, so that you can actually remember your word. Whenever I've worked with hybrid such and others, do you feel that you've got so many important points there.
Krish NAik: Because maximum, if I check.
Krish NAik: every point of time in a normal vector search, I won't say that you will be getting so many points. The point might be lesser, because it's totally based on the chance, okay? But I feel that the response here is much better.
Krish NAik: Okay, so there, yes, you will be getting, but lesser point. In high-level questions, I feel that GraphRab actually performs better, because that needs to be broken down into multiple other questions, and that's actually where Nudes plays a crucial role with your relationship.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now, this is the actual implementation, really. Okay. Now, after that, if we want to perform some type of graph.
Krish NAik: based. Okay, now this is a direct cipher Q&A that I have applied here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you want to really pass based on text… now, what is the main purpose is to generate some type of
Krish NAik: How many of you know text-to-SQL?
Krish NAik: Guys, text to SQL.
Krish NAik: Now, the same thing if you try to do text-to- see, the main thing is text-to-sequit.
Krish NAik: Previously, we have discussed SQL, the normal SQL, but here, sequel, okay?
Krish NAik: That's the same stuff that we are trying to do, if you want to do the analyze of this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, a direct, functionality is there, okay, and based on that, like, climate impact, human activities, ecosystems, seasons, production, water, okay, these are the things. Now, this is direct… a text-to-SQL task that I have done, because this chain is directly available
Krish NAik: inside your Neo4J. Can you see? This is a direct Neo4J implementation that I have taken, not directly available in Langchain, but based on your Graph database, this operation is available.
Krish NAik: And see, this is the generated cipher.
Krish NAik: And the same thing, you can execute it where?
Krish NAik: Directly on top of the database.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I'm telling. So, this is a text-to-SQL thing that I have done, pretty much, but it's not that SQL, it's CQL.
Krish NAik: Hybrid is a better approach, for sure, hybrid will be better. This is… I'm just directly showing you, because as you guys have already done, Text2SQL, this is also one example of Text2SQL.
Krish NAik: All right, guys, so I feel that this part is done. Now we can actually go for a break, and then we will continue, okay? In the meantime, let me take some questions, okay? So let's start my timer.
Krish NAik: Where is Cielo City?
Krish NAik: Totally clean.
Krish NAik: Let me bring it here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I will start a 10-minute simmer, and then we will continue.
Krish NAik: All right, now I think I can take some questions. People, please raise your hand. There's a lot of theoretical stuff that we have discussed.
Krish NAik: Unkosh, you have raised your ants for others also.
Krish NAik: No. No, no, no, page index is different now, okay? Page index I'll be taking, don't worry.
Krish NAik: We have a… okay, Ankush, I think you can go ahead.
Krish NAik: why I'm not getting any audio, just wait. I think my mic… my mic is thin. I think. Guys, please try. Ankush or whoever anyone, please go ahead.
Vaibhav Gandhi: Hey, am I audible?
Krish NAik: Yeah, you are welcome.
Krish NAik: After that, whenever we were audible, please go ahead.
Vaibhav Gandhi: Okay, so, I have a question. So, Matesha, I'm using somebody else's, room right now.
Krish NAik: Sorry, I forgot you. Yeah.
Vaibhav Gandhi: So, basically, I have used the same kind of approach of using a land graph.
Vaibhav Gandhi: Next to SQL, okay? We're using WANA.
Vaibhav Gandhi: where I pass schemas in a MD and JSON files, and tried doing that. It gave me a good answer, but do you think I should, use, graph retrieval, graph rack, for schema retrievers in that particular bit?
Krish NAik: No, no, SQL, when you are telling normal, like, Postgres or something like that only, you are telling no. Yes, not CyberQuery.
Vaibhav Gandhi: The query has to be generated, right?
Krish NAik: In that case, I will say Vana is much better. With Vana, the best…
Vaibhav Gandhi: I didn't wanna… Why not?
Krish NAik: A year ago.
Vaibhav Gandhi: Yeah, dude, what?
Krish NAik: Yep, y'all.
Krish NAik: I will say that is better there.
Vaibhav Gandhi: We'll try, and I will come back to you next year.
Krish NAik: Nice.
Krish NAik: Now, Abhisit is asking, Hi Paul, is it necessary to learn Langrap to build the agency? See, guys, like, which is why I feel it is important, we are in the Langchen ecosystem. Okay, and in that LangChain ecosystem, like, Langrap is one part. It's not necessary that you learn that.
Krish NAik: one framework is more than enough. Like, Creo AI, okay, then you have that, Agnew is there, okay, Pyntic AI is there, like, see, many frameworks, Strand AI is there, like, right now in the market, there are more than 40 to 50, like, these type of frameworks are there.
Krish NAik: At least, because Langraph, I… if you really say then, I think the Microsoft Agentic one that is there, again, the older name was AutoGen. Many frameworks, but at least learn one framework, and if you know one framework, it becomes easier to switch to anything.
Krish NAik: And most of the AI community is working with Langchain.
Krish NAik: So, the first step, they start with Langraph also.
Krish NAik: That's why the main thing that I feel that ESU should know a little bit of playing around.
Krish NAik: Okay, Hankush… I've asked you to unmute yourself, Ankush.
Krish NAik: And push on, push.
Krish NAik: Okay, no response.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine, then I will lower your hand.
Krish NAik: think about in what level that you can do the definition. Here's based on degree programs, if you have an ontology for different degree programs.
Krish NAik: we need to classify given degree. You can think about in high level how you can do it. For example, based on degrees, first of all, let's make, like, one step first level of differentiation, should we? Like, like.
Krish NAik: undergrad, grad, post-grad, postdoc, in that way, you can actually do the classification. Okay, then the next level, like, what will be the core things, like, based on CS, EC, those ways that you can do it? Yes, you can do that.
Krish NAik: I feel that, because based on your degree programs, yes, you can do. You need to classify a given degree. Yes, you can use classified, simply, because I know these things won't change, and later on, if something gets added, probably a new degree comes into the picture. For that, you can actually add a new one.
Krish NAik: So, yes, this really works, Aruna.
Krish NAik: Now, Muthaza, how big the graph and the relation are good to use without hallucinations?
Krish NAik: I would really say to avoid hallucinations, like using LLMs for that discovering of that entity relationship is bad.
Krish NAik: To avoid hallucinations, it's better to go ahead with an NER model, a custom NER model based on your data.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, I feel that, if the graph
Krish NAik: becomes bigger. And if the LLM makes a mistake, though, if you apply a lot of rules, strict rules, follow only these, then also… because the processing time for the LLM will be much higher, so custom engineer models are much better.
Krish NAik: Okay, and because my main purpose is not to make dynamic changes to the graph.
Krish NAik: Okay, so make lesser changes, I think.
Krish NAik: Okay, and Vichita's asking, the AI is changing, and the, it's getting difficult, learning new things, so how do you suggest this?
Krish NAik: Sorry, okay, now, Vichy, your question is a bit different, okay, but most of us always remember that, how big the graph and the…
Krish NAik: it can be big. It means that the setup nodes can be, like,
Krish NAik: Started can be, like, it can be very, very high.
Krish NAik: like, 1,000, 10,000, 20,000, that's why craft database. And it's actually a scalable, but remember that you should maintain that particular should not be dynamically over-increasing it. You increase it, fine, but always do a research before adding any type of node.
Krish NAik: Okay, because if you actually add one node, a lot of other things that needs to be, changed dynamically.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because just think about the metadata. So, for your other chunks, also, the metadata for that one node also, you have to keep it as none, and later on, you have to update it for your vector DM information also, if you are performing a hybrid search.
Krish NAik: I feel that, yes.
Krish NAik: But it's a good practice, actually, because I feel that graph rags are very, very good. It's very, very good. But that's the only thing. Maintaining that ontology is the most important.
Krish NAik: If you're not maintaining, then using GraphRag is a total waste of time.
Krish NAik: Again, always remember these things. If it's… the number of documents are small, it will work. As it keeps on growing, it means that you are taking the step one. Failure 1% to failure 100%. As…
Krish NAik: exponentially the number of documents. Increases your system will
Krish NAik: Failed very, very badly, and the rate of hallucination will increase very, very high.
Krish NAik: How do we select NER models? Select any type. NER models, you can easily get it, no? I think everybody knows Hugging Face.
Krish NAik: models from there, wherever you can get, like, sorry, Methesh. Or use the spicy NER, it is also used in industries a lot. Two options that I'm telling you, you can always use them.
Krish NAik: Similarity check for two graphs, it means run a similarity check when you say, it means that based on some distance.
Krish NAik: You can apply these on the attributes, but directly not top on the nodes. It means, see, in the nodes, you'll be having some attributes, so those two attributes you can actually check.
Krish NAik: But directly not on top of the node.
Krish NAik: That part, I want to make it clear.
Krish NAik: You can actually, like, if you are going with an hop system, like, reach till the last node, there you can actually use it, because till how much you want to do the traversal, it is also important.
Krish NAik: So always select an optimal number going till the last node is not a good… it means, again, the latency increases.
Krish NAik: For me, that particular direction of multi-hub, like, step 1, step 2, step 3, it becomes much easier for the LLM to understand that entire relation, starting from which node.
Krish NAik: Okay, till the last one. But if you give that idea to the LLM, the LLM gets a better overall context that, yes, you are going in the right direction.
Krish NAik: But somehow, if you have selected your initial top 3 to 4 nodes that's wrong, it becomes a problem.
Krish NAik: In subgraph, even in the subgraph also, like, node is part of the subgraph.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Because, see, similarity check is done on top of your vectors, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: I don't… Simple concept. Cosine similarity, do you think non-direct graph part, you can add it? Not possible.
Krish NAik: Okay. Similarity means it has to be vectors. Now, the same vector, you are actually saving it for your hybrid search in your vector deal. On top of that, it means through an attribute, you can access the vectors, and those two vectors, you can actually do the comparison.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I will just stop sharing this one. Okay, in the meantime, everybody, for your next…
Krish NAik: I think… Let me just close this one.
Krish NAik: Cambridge, Lord.
Krish NAik: I don't want me on fortitude.
Krish NAik: Please use, it was food.
Krish NAik: in 100.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please.
Krish NAik: Do the setup for this one, vector property.
Krish NAik: This is also as simple, because here you have the main notebook, so the main notebook should be up in…
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: I think I've already shared the data, this is much more JSON, and actually, I feel that for graph databases, I prefer the data based on JSON, because JSON always maintains the structure.
Krish NAik: I prefer working, like, whenever for my Graph databases, I randomly picking up flat files, like PDF.
Krish NAik: I prefer to at least create it into some conventional structure, and then directly path it for my grab operations, okay? Now, this thing that I am telling, always remember. Okay, now it is used widely, everywhere, but, you should also follow this rule.
Krish NAik: Just to it, okay?
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: Okay, now for the data parsing.
Krish NAik: So, if you have a PDF,
Krish NAik: If you're not working with graph databases, then I always say, for example, if you're working with Docklin.
Krish NAik: Always say that, okay, Docklink is a good one, or if you're working with unstructured, always try to create a…
Krish NAik: intermediate form.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I prefer Markdown, most of the times MD format.
Krish NAik: Now, from this markdown to rest of the things, it means that whatever the chunk.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then to VDB, that I want to perform, or vector database.
Krish NAik: Okay? No!
Krish NAik: But in the case of graphs, okay, the same thing, don't use Markdown, rather than use JSON.
Krish NAik: JSON always maintain a structure of key value, and that key value actually plays a crucial role, okay? So, for your, grab these documents, try to create some type of an algorithm which will actually help you to do the conversion.
Krish NAik: from that PDF to JSON to SAMHA.
Krish NAik: Yeah, because I feel that, working with JSON files for your graph traversal is better as compared to Markdown files.
Krish NAik: So this is just an important thing. I feel that from practicality also, I feel that JSON always maintain that structure.
Krish NAik: Okay, so use an intermediate. Most of the times, in major use cases, you will see directly PDF and that. But actually, in…
Krish NAik: Other systems, it's a good practice to keep an intermediate format, and here's JSON, it can be YML also.
Krish NAik: Okay, YMLs also work, but I prefer much more JSON.
Krish NAik: XML also, you can keep it, but JSONs are my main preference.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now, let's go back to our advanced theme 3.
Krish NAik: Alright, I hope everybody has taken the clone and they have done the setup. Please provide a confirmation so that we can move ahead.
Krish NAik: Or should I wait 2 minutes?
Krish NAik: There will be more.
Krish NAik: More, I think. 15 sessions, believe it, 12 to 15 minutes.
Krish NAik: We have a lot of things to discuss. Few things that got famous right now, in the past.
Krish NAik: Because right now, like, see, RAG is something like an open ocean. It means that it has a lot of depth, and the research is still now ongoing.
Krish NAik: Somebody might say, because I have seen some blogs, like, RAG is dead, but it's not actually dead.
Krish NAik: Okay, sometimes, like, I feel that… about that, FS, that's the file exploration.
Krish NAik: in your local-based systems, okay, so for that, writing some rules. I'll be talking about that in probably Project 5, where actually give access to your local system, okay, a few operations, like, in your system, like, corrupt.
Krish NAik: Okay, then file rate commands, those type of operations, so through that, you can do it. I'll be talking about, till now. Because this month, also, a lot of papers that came around.
Krish NAik: I don't know the latest paper of RAG that I was reading, it was hyperbolic RAG.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, I feel that, like, it's an ongoing research, and I don't know, like, till now, things are pretty much trendy. I don't see the complete downfall of RAG, at least this year, but I feel that.
Krish NAik: Claude Kohler does the test exactly.
Krish NAik: The same thing, we can actually do it by our, system also. Like, in my local, if I put 10 documents, I can give access and everything, I can do it.
Krish NAik: But a local file system-based agent that I need to create in that agent should have access to certain commands.
Krish NAik: So, please let me know guys at TAR.
Krish NAik: Are you guys ready?
Krish NAik: This is a mood book that I'll be executing, so just be sure everything works.
Krish NAik: And here I have the data. So if I show you the data now, these are all JSON files.
Krish NAik: As I was talking about JSON files, so in this example, I actually have taken input JSON files. I feel that these are much important, okay? And if you want to actually visualize.
Krish NAik: Do I have a JSON viewer? Just wait. I do have a JSON viewer.
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: Alright, I think I have this bike.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think this is one. Okay, now, yes.
Krish NAik: Now, see, this is a set of document, the general information.
Krish NAik: It rigs and… Okay, then comes your, like, compartment. Now, here, multiple tags that we have created, actually.
Krish NAik: This is really, like, for one set of documents, but here, actually, I'm passing it in the form of key value. I feel that if you are working with key-value stores, it becomes much easier for you to create the graphs, so that's why maintaining a certain structure rather than a flat document. Okay, so this is the main purpose of taking JSON files here.
Krish NAik: In your case, I can say that if you're working with a certain problem statement, and if you feel that your data is pretty much static, the structure is static, can I say that you can define a static JSON file for your data?
Krish NAik: Yes, if you can define that static JSON, okay, for your incoming data, I can say that yes, at least. Later on, it's fine that you maintain that structure on top of this structure if you add something. That is acceptable, but at least don't…
Krish NAik: Break the structure.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's why it means that some new key value you might have added, that is acceptable, but the existing or the old structure needs to be formed.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I've kept it here, based on this. Do we… we do not have the data folder, please commit. You don't have the data folder, guys?
Krish NAik: Yes, okay, no, no, no, no, no. Alright, fine, fine. I don't know, in my system, by default, in gitignore, how that comes. Every time. Just wait, I will create a new folder, okay?
Krish NAik: We'll come across…
Krish NAik: Indeed.
Krish NAik: Alright, I have shared it in a different folder, the Datadocs folder, please do have a check.
Krish NAik: Let me check my .gitign. Are there JSON files.json.json.json?
Krish NAik: It's not there only, then I don't know how it…
Krish NAik: Okay, fine, everybody please, take the data, because the data is important. If you guys cannot
Krish NAik: load the data, then again. Just do a git pull, guys, everybody. I think the data docs, I have added it right now, and you have this. Okay, so in your case, please update the path. Like, in my case, I'm using the data.
Krish NAik: But, in your case, please use DataOps.
Krish NAik: I think you guys are smart, so you can actually take that decision.
Krish NAik: Once, you are ready, please let me know in the chat so that we can start with the execution.
Krish NAik: The requirement.txt file is missing.
Krish NAik: Satya Narayana, Vanguarda is selling requirement.txt, so…
Krish NAik: First of all, why you need requirement.txt?
Krish NAik: I think I have made a gradual shift in your course.
Krish NAik: from requirement.txt to pyproject.2ml, I hope everybody agrees on that.
Krish NAik: Yes, because it's much easier, you have to just do an UV sync.
Krish NAik: Satanaram.
Krish NAik: That's why, see, by requirement.txt, I can create it and share it with you, but again, like, I'm sharing pyproject.2ml. That's why I'm not sharing, okay?
Krish NAik: Because going forward, like, 50% of the course requirement, it's an old thing, but in 2025, everybody has moved to 2ML format. So, using 2ML much more.
Krish NAik: Alright, so the first thing that I will do, I hope everybody has taken the poll. I need a, database, okay? So for this particular database configuration, if I go to my, .env, so let me see, like, what are the things are there.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me just… Deak…
Krish NAik: Admin1235, okay, and a few things. Okay, so let me just create a new one for now.
Krish NAik: Where is my Neo 4J, Neo 4J? Yes, here I have my Neo 4J. Local instances.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… let me stop this one.
Krish NAik: I'm just creating the instance according to my configuration, so you guys also be sure.
Krish NAik: Okay, and don't use the old instance. It's better you can stop it and create a new one. Deleting is not necessary, but if you want to delete it, that is also fine.
Krish NAik: Mmm, epoch Plugin added. Epoch Plugin added, yes.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I feel that the main configuration is done.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now 4G. And, the OpenAI… okay, so if you feel that OpenAI base URL, this is pretty much the same one, I will update the example, I feel that it will be better.
Krish NAik: Big one.
Krish NAik: dot ENB updated.
Krish NAik: It can take the base URL also, I'm committing that also.
Krish NAik: This is the default one. Whenever you are working with any, I can say LLMs, so you do have a base URL, and based on that base URL, you change that.
Krish NAik: Anybody has changed the base URL? Any point of time, like in Anthropic?
Krish NAik: In codecs, they're actually, like, you can work with Cloud Code, but you can bring a cheaper model.
Krish NAik: like GLM, Minimax, and you can make it work in Cloud Code. So there, you have to actually update your base URL.
Krish NAik: All right, fine. So, I have added that, so I think you guys can take it. So, the first thing that I will do is let's connect to a database. So, a direct, pretty much, stuff that I'm taking it from ingest.neo4j. Now, see, guys.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a high-level script. It means that if I show you create notes.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, see, from ingest…
Krish NAik: Now, this is important, because now… let me just… now, font is clear, or should I increase the font? Please tell me.
Krish NAik: Increase? Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, I mean, I'm not ingesting a lot, but this is actually modular code. So, first of all, I have ingest, see. In this ingest folder, this is the… ingest means what? Document ingestion in your rack that happens, so that's why I created that ingest folder. In that, you have one
Krish NAik: file, which is the Neo4ja module, okay? And in this NEO4GF module, you have a function of creating the nodes.
Krish NAik: While you need to create nodes, I hope that it is pretty much self-explanatory, okay? Now, here, in this, particular Neo4j, dev create nodes, so first of all, graph, and you can see the Neo4J. Now, this is what I'm calling. Now, this is actual initialization, through which it will be making the connection.
Krish NAik: Then comes your original data that will be incoming from your JSON, then comes your node level, okay?
Krish NAik: And then comes your node name, so all this definition, I need, then only I can create a node.
Krish NAik: I hope this is self-explanatory, guys.
Krish NAik: To create a node, you need an actual database connection, you need the data, you need to define a node level, you need to define the node name. Two things.
Krish NAik: Now, here I'm passing the mean date query. Okay, so here, see, now this is actually a… what type of operation, a cipher query operation that I have done. Through that operation, I will be performing what? I'll be creating a node. So, what is the benefit of using merge?
Krish NAik: merge, like, if I only use create node, create cannot actually check the condition that whether something is existing or not, but merge actually first checks, then creates. So that's why I've used that merge here.
Krish NAik: Then comes graph.query, passing the mean.query with all the params that we have passed it, okay? Now, here for section in content in data.item, we are passing the query, and finally, like, the mean draft query that we'll be creating, okay? Now.
Krish NAik: As simple, so this is the creating node part.
Krish NAik: Alright, once the note, then comes the second part, which is the pinecone. Now, why I've taken this implementation? There is a purpose.
Krish NAik: In the last example of Langchain.
Krish NAik: I have taken, Neo4j, if you remember for our vector databases, but how many of you think
Krish NAik: That your organization will take Neo4j as your main vector database.
Krish NAik: Because Neo4ja vector database support is there.
Krish NAik: But it's not very good, as compared to Milverse, as compared to Quadrant. It's there, but again, you have to understand that, there are certain organizations, and their products are good in
Krish NAik: certain things. I cannot say that every organization has its product, and it is good and overall. So that's why, like, generally, I prefer to keep both the things separate rather than keeping
Krish NAik: everything in one shot. So here, I have taken pine cones. The idea is that later on you change… you can change it to quadrant, you can change it to millverse, so vector TV should be different, and your graph, vector database should be different.
Krish NAik: So, pinecone ingestion part. So, here, so in the pinecone ingestion, I'm using the recursive text splitter, JSON, okay, config.lllm client, so here, if I go.
Krish NAik: say, client, the OpenAI API key that I'll be picking up from .env, so from OpenAI. Can you see the actual package? I'm not using Langchen OpenAI package, so purely directly, I'm utilizing. And in Project 2, I've already shown you, like, you can directly work with the
Krish NAik: Pinecone package also, and the OpenAI package. You don't need Langchain as a wrapper, always.
Krish NAik: Alright, but here for text splitting that I have taken Langchen.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes PC.index, so this is a pinecone index we'll be checking, then after that comes processing and upset operation. It means that you'll be uploading your chunk-based operation with respect to your VDB, so all those information is there. It's pretty much classical Pinecone indexing that we have discussed in Module 2. There is nothing new here.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody remembers in Project 2, we have discussed and spent a lot of time, so I've taken it fine code. Now, this can be anything. This is simple VDV operation, a simple vector database operation, there is nothing fancy here.
Krish NAik: Alright, the only new thing that got added, which was the Neo 4J module that I have added it here.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the ingestion phase. Now, in the retrieval, you have the new 4G and Pinecone. Now, why I need both of these things?
Krish NAik: To create something like an on-thermal retriever.
Krish NAik: I hope you get it. Like, in the last notebook, I showed a very similar strategy that we'll be working at here.
Krish NAik: Alright, so first of all, dev, search, and phase. Okay, now this is where your Neo4j query string that I am passing it here. So, what are the things? First of all, I am loading the graph, the Neo4j graph, and load new 4J.
Krish NAik: Okay, now for this, under the configuration, I have this new version.py. Loading the graph, it means what? Simply making a connection. Making a connection to our graph database.
Krish NAik: Once the connection is loaded, simply get pinecone. Now, again, what is this get pinecone? This is connection to your pinecone.
Krish NAik: Now, okay, both the connections are ready. Then comes PC.index. Now, this is where your Pinecone index definition, we will check, the index is available or not, through the Pinecone host. Pinecone host is basically the index URL. I hope everybody understands.
Krish NAik: I don't need to show you the pine cone.
Krish NAik: You white?
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Because Pinecone UI, I'm not showing you, but I hope everybody gets it.
Krish NAik: Everybody remembers?
Krish NAik: No, people are telling.
Krish NAik: Sampat is telling, no, okay, I don't need to show Frank, no, okay? Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, search and fetch, the idea is to use this initialized variable here. So, first of all, client.embittings.create. We know that for every, piece of text.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the embedding the query that I'll be, receiving. Okay, so the new 4J query.
Krish NAik: and the query. If you really think about, both will be in the string formats. The return type, the top query that I have taken only as 2 for now. Okay, the written type of this function will be a list dictionary. Then comes your query embedding. Query means a question that is asked by the user, manually I am creating it.
Krish NAik: In Langchen, Langshan takes care of it. Directly, you can…
Krish NAik: pass that query, and you can make an actual, like, a search operation, or a dense search. But right now, this is only for my main query that I'm doing. Now, once I have my query embedding, now using the query embedding, I can actually
Krish NAik: make a call in both of my places. Okay, so this is where result is equal to index.query, there I am passing my query embedding.
Krish NAik: Okay, top K include metastata is equal to true. This is for pinecone-specific implementation that I have done it. This is pure pinecone-based implementation.
Krish NAik: Now, once I have my final results, so here…
Krish NAik: I'm creating a blank list, because I need to…
Krish NAik: Add the results. This is the vector
Krish NAik: a return type, and this is the graph result. So, for match in result.matches, score is equal to match.score, match.metadata. Now, once I have this particular information, can you see that I am using this metadata information?
Krish NAik: in GraphQuery, so I'm actually telling you that the output
Krish NAik: of your vector DB, you can actually utilize it.
Krish NAik: Because the same metadata is utilized in your, graph
Krish NAik: vector database also. So, actually, through that, you can do it. So, it actually gives you a much better added benefit, okay, and somehow optimizing your graph cell also.
Krish NAik: So I feel that this is important. Now, there are more ways of optimization, but this is one of them that I feel that anybody can utilize it.
Krish NAik: From one result, you can actually manipulate the other result also.
Krish NAik: Metashi solving, can you explain the metadata with one example? Metadata? Like, any type of metadata definition that you are doing?
Krish NAik: the same metadata you are keeping. It means that in both the cases, the metadata is same. You're not changing the metadata. If you're not changing the metadata, so in the first case, if you have one result, with that result.
Krish NAik: you have the metadata in the output also. That output of the vector search, actually, you were using it in the draft reversal. That was the main purpose.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, finally, you can see final result. One is this result, one is this graph result, both the things I am adding it here, and this is the final thing that will be written.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is one way that I have shown.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think all the major modules I have discussed are now.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, let's create the connection.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think, it should work. Everybody, please do have a check with UVSync. The first cell is working. If something is not working, there is some issue with respect to your module or your installation part. Okay? Everybody, please check and let me know this part is working.
Krish NAik: The first cell.
Krish NAik: Everybody.
Krish NAik: Because sometimes, if you have not done the installation correctly, it, might create an issue. And here, actually, if I show you my pyproject.2ml.
Krish NAik: Can you see here?
Krish NAik: These RMI, I've defined them as packages here, ingest, retrieve, and config.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I have defined it so there won't be any type of problem, okay?
Krish NAik: All right. Now, This, particular…
Krish NAik: implementation, I think I have taken it already. Now, let's take, the next part.
Krish NAik: Which is the, defining the databases, so…
Krish NAik: three type of JSON files that I have, okay? So, if you remember here, let's go to the data folder, in your case, Datadocs. Battle of Waterloo, Napoleon, okay, and I think Talent.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the first file, Napoleon, labeled as a person node in Neo4je. Okay, now this is much more about giving a structure for your
Krish NAik: File, this is the percent node.
Krish NAik: Okay, that we want. Then comes, like, okay, the talent, this is also labeled as a person.
Krish NAik: And actually, if you actually go inside these files, I knew that.
Krish NAik: they will have much more information. But finally, I can say that, okay, let's start with the first level of node, person node. Okay. Then, after that, subnodes that we can actually define.
Krish NAik: Then, Napoleon, Talerant, and then comes, finally, the Battle of… this is pretty much like an event based on the other node. So I can say that, okay, the main node can be a subnote. So, probably the next, first, the person that…
Krish NAik: event can be connected to that particular person. Okay, so pretty much, like, 3 entities for now, person, person, and event.
Krish NAik: So, I'm just passing the filenames for now, the mean file names, and I know that all those are .json, so directly I can pass them to read it. So, for that, I have, I think.
Krish NAik: The recursive text character split up from…
Krish NAik: Okay, from pneumo4U, not from you. I think in our ingestion, here I had that. Okay, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: First part I have loaded. Second part also let me load it.
Krish NAik: These are all fine names. Now, in your case, just be sure you are passing the correct one. Now, see, in your config, please go to config once.
Krish NAik: I want to just check that, operation once.
Krish NAik: Alright, this part is fine, there is no issue with that, okay?
Krish NAik: In the main config, NEO4J, this is also fine.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. So, I think for everybody, this part, should work.
Krish NAik: Please pass the final names, because the final names definition that we have already done it, okay? Now, see, from this file names, I need to create those notes, okay? So that's why. Now, this part, I have kept it as a commit. Please try to understand exactly what we are trying to do. The main node
Krish NAik: First of all, main node, with that, the subnodes or the section nodes that I have retained in this particular file.
Krish NAik: So, the first node is pretty much, like, the person node that will come, the Napoleon file, then you have the Scalaran, another person, and then comes the event.
Krish NAik: So, 3 main nodes, okay? Then with the subnodes, now this is the information that I'll be getting from inside the file. So, the general information, because from every file, I have these three structures. General information, career, and I, like, type depth, so you can actually do the analysis of this file.
Krish NAik: Okay, so general information after general information, I think some other things. Okay, so in this case, only general information is there. Okay, I think in the next file, in the Napoleon one, there is…
Krish NAik: General information, career, and depth. Okay, and here, again, death. Now, this is much more about a person, so for sure, this Battle of Waterloo is an event, so there cannot be a depth parameter for an event. I hope everybody gets that.
Krish NAik: Okay, for this particular event, only the general information which is available. For the other two persons, yes, some reason, combatment, and, like, consequence and those things are there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the event. For the event, the subnode information will be different. For person, the subnode information will be different.
Krish NAik: So here, first of all, the note definition, 2 person, one event. Now, let's analyze the file. Once you read the file, then you will be getting the information, general information, career, date for now.
Krish NAik: Now, why merge instead of create? Already, I told you the logic. According to Neo4j. Merge means create this node only if this does not exist. So, if something is already… so I've used merge, it's a bad practice to work with create directly in Neo4j.
Krish NAik: Oh…
Krish NAik: Unam Nanda is telling, I didn't join the last class, my new 4G connection not working. Say, if your new 4G connection is not working, you have to do the installation.
Krish NAik: Okay, because otherwise I cannot do anything. I think everybody has done, like, last Saturday I've discussed that.
Krish NAik: I created the instance… please do have it checked, because,
Krish NAik: my.engv, if I show you. Just wait.
Krish NAik: This is how it looks like.
Krish NAik: Bold. Okay, if you have just remembered bold, so these are my configurations, so just be sure you are using Semin, otherwise I will look into your issue later on.
Krish NAik: Now, the first level done, so we need to create my main nodes, then my subnodes.
Krish NAik: Now, here I'm telling for name in filename, so here the data. In your case, you have to change this name of the folder. I think you guys are smart, here you can pass.
Krish NAik: And update your folder name.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Because in your case, I have passed Datadocs, okay? So please, according to that, please change it.
Krish NAik: All right, now, open the JSON file, pretty much a simple Pythonic operation, the same thing can be done using LanChain, but I didn't feel you need to use LanChain just to read a file.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes, okay, if the name is equal to Battle of Waterloo, create subnodes. Can you see here? Node-level event. Now, this is the structure and the rule that I am following.
Krish NAik: please analyze this part, because your mood level is different. One mood level is event, the other one is for person. And you are passing the original data that you are actually reading from which file.
Krish NAik: So, here I've added a condition, so based on this particular file that I am doing. But in production, this particular logic needs to be much more robust. And can anybody tell me how you can make it much more robust?
Krish NAik: Like, see, this analysis is really tough, in a true sense, if I say.
Krish NAik: Because this is the first level of building your subnode. So, if you have fixed set, then you can actually do analysis through this. Like, okay, now, in high level, this document through an NER model also, you can do it. Okay, by taking multiple set of NKTs, you can decide that, okay, this is what type.
Krish NAik: of document it is related to something, but yes, the logic can be different. So, it's not a simple set, so you have to define your own pseudo-algorithm, and based on that data analysis results, you have to come to a solution.
Krish NAik: Because for now, directly based on file name, but I simply tell you, this is not a very robust technique. When you have 10,000 files, really, this won't work.
Krish NAik: Because the if-and-else condition will… Alright, now let me just… Read the files.
Krish NAik: So, node created, alright, nodes are created. So, you can actually grow here, let me see.
Krish NAik: Okay, so can I do the visualization right now? Please tell me. Is it possible to do the visualization now?
Krish NAik: Simply, I've created notes. Have I created any relationship?
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: All right, so let's move in the next step.
Krish NAik: nodes created, then comes create relationship, because what is relationship? The edge between two nodes. As simple as that, we call it.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, here, the relationship, so this is related to now, you know that whenever we are creating the relationship, we have to give some type of name. Related to has section or something like that, contains… okay. Now, and generally, like, we can create it by relation always, if you feel that. I don't feel that this is always important.
Krish NAik: Okay, but, if you feel, like, if you use, like, contents, contents should be unidirectional, but if it's related, if you feel in both the ways, like, from a chunk, if you want to go to the document, it's good.
Krish NAik: But it's always a bad practice that from the chunk, you should always go to the main document, because the main document will be much bigger information.
Krish NAik: And if you really feel that you need to trigger through all the chunks.
Krish NAik: Which I feel that every time it is not important, okay? Like, getting that high-level idea about… because your document can be very, very big, so directly, so you can define that relationship, whether you need a unidirectional relationship or a bidirectional relationship.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, the safest way is bi-directional, but always remember the latency will be higher, but
Krish NAik: the results will be better, but if you want to make your traversal much more faster, working with unidirectionals are much more better. Those are graph database fundamentals, so really, I don't want to give a lot of focus on that.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, once I have created, now, what are these operations? Quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: What are these operations? These are relationship-based operations that we are doing. See, I have added this, and I am performing CQL, Cypher query language operation. Here, I am passing directly inside a variable. Relationship percent to percent. It means that if I want to create a relationship between Napoleon and
Krish NAik: Talaran. Then comes person to event. If I want to create a relationship between the Battle of Waterloo with Napoleon.
Krish NAik: Okay. In that, we are created. And then, finally, person to section, because every node will be having a subsection. So, for that particular subsection relationship also, it is required. In that way, multiple event to section.
Krish NAik: So, every possible scenario, you need to handle it. Because this is node to subnode. So, first of all, node level.
Krish NAik: Then, sub-node living. I hope you get it. In that way, I'm creating the relationships here.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: All relationships created successfully?
Krish NAik: Okay, so… here I have just added the print state… see, here…
Krish NAik: for queries in queries, graph.query. If I have executed the query.
Krish NAik: Now, what will happen? Just tell me.
Krish NAik: Now, this reload feature here, really, just wait. Let me go here, let me go here again.
Krish NAik: Hmm… Alright.
Krish NAik: Because two relationships, I can see, has section and related to, which is available, but again, But,
Krish NAik: Let me just check this one.
Krish NAik: Alright, just wait. Let me do the ingestion once, and then I will finally look into this one.
Krish NAik: Because right now, I feel that only the, I have just made the quail for now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so ingest into pinecone vector embedding now, this is the pinecone part.
Krish NAik: Okay, I hope this works, because really, I have not tested my pinecone. Last week only, I have done it. But it looks like the upset operation is working, with respect to the index and other things.
Krish NAik: Okay, and now, guys, this is not an asynchronous operation, a simple sync operation, that's why it's taking time.
Krish NAik: Because every point of time, for me, it's not necessary, but for you guys, always use asynchronous operation for these type of things.
Krish NAik: Inserted 121 chunks for Talerant, just on, okay, now coming to the next set of document.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I can see only two relationships are there, so based on that relation.
Krish NAik: Okay, my main relationships, but this graph…
Krish NAik: Okay, now once I have this graph, then this relationship within your subnodes will be much more clear.
Krish NAik: On… And this is your main node, how to understand this underscore info. Always remember that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… It gives you a high-level idea with respect to exactly.
Krish NAik: This is the first level of note, that through that, I can always do an identification of the name. That's why I've kept it at underscore info. So, similarly, in complex graphs, you keep it, like, level 1, level 2, level 3, level 4, level 5.
Krish NAik: through name, if you want to actually apply a filter level logic, in the name only, I keep that, which level it comes from.
Krish NAik: Let me see whether the first level… How much time?
Krish NAik: Okay, till now, only Document 1.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's sweet.
Krish NAik: Later on, please optimize this piece of code so that it supports asynchronous operations.
Krish NAik: Okay, in the second document, 316, alright.
Krish NAik: Third document will be faster, because this is just an event, I feel, the Battle of Waterloo.
Krish NAik: There will be a dimension issue, dimension issue with respect to what? Embedding dimension issue, there won't be any type of problem.
Krish NAik: Because that you are maintaining in your vector team.
Krish NAik: Pinecone Index,
Krish NAik: See, Pinecone Index, I don't feel, 5 Pinecone Index, because in mine, somewhere around, I remember, I've kept at 1536.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I don't think there will be any index-level problems.
Krish NAik: Somewhere, I don't remember, but,
Krish NAik: I have kept that parameter of 1536 somewhere in the code.
Krish NAik: Neo Forager, Pine Foon…
Krish NAik: Because I know that the default one, if I've not kept it, you have to understand the default one for text embedding 3 small, the default one is 1536.
Krish NAik: And manually, if you want to do the alteration of that.
Krish NAik: Like, 512, because it supports multi-dimensions, but the default one is always 1536, that's it.
Krish NAik: Jatin is telling the depth, search, and fetch, alright.
Krish NAik: And the search and… this is in your retrieval, I think.
Krish NAik: Oh, gosh.
Krish NAik: Alright, anywhere, see, Jateindar, I have not passed anywhere 1536.
Krish NAik: If you really see, I don't…
Krish NAik: See here? So, I'm telling. By default, I know that takes time within 3 small takes that dimension, so I don't think there will be any problem.
Krish NAik: But line number 13 you were telling.
Krish NAik: Text embedding 3 small. Yes.
Krish NAik: This is the model I have selected, no.
Krish NAik: And I know the default setting of this model is 1536. So when you are actually creating your Pinecone index, there.
Krish NAik: I will check it then. Okay, I'll wait.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, let's see, like, how much got executed here. Okay, so just wait.
Krish NAik: Alright, I can see 121, 121, 101 total, 755 total chunks inserted.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, fine, now comes defining the graph to ourself query, read the query again, okay.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the part with respect to… so if I do a query.search, what will happen?
Krish NAik: Now, just tell me, like, what is the meaning of this?
Krish NAik: If I directly pass this and fire this query, what will happen?
Krish NAik: Okay, you guys know that this is pure SQL, but our object is to do something like a hybrid-based approach.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I will make this crawlable right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Now, if you really look into the results of the graph, okay, now, based on that, who killed Napoleon? So, who killed Napoleon? So, where should it go? Into which node? This is very important.
Krish NAik: Absolutely, man, let me move forward.
Krish NAik: Why this doesn't get loaded up.
Krish NAik: This is actually a problem, I feel.
Krish NAik: Because this one, if I want to do.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, this is with respect to relationship-lating pupas.
Krish NAik: Actually, see, generally, it should show you in the graph, okay, because if I try to restart this, and sometimes one of this is a problem with your local one. But directly, I'm showing you the relationship here. Can you see the relationship directly?
Krish NAik: Okay, now I asked a question with respect to Napoleon with water upload. So I can see that, okay, person to event
Krish NAik: is there. Okay, but my question that I had was very specific only to Napoleon, and the death of Napoleon.
Krish NAik: Okay, because, that, death will be a subnode information.
Krish NAik: So…
Krish NAik: Let's get back here. So, if I show you… can you see here? First of all, okay, this code that I'm getting here, section is death, because from JSON,
Krish NAik: I think Napoleon. Napoleon has this death one.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, percent node. Under that percent node, you have this death.
Krish NAik: How many of you get this? Because the main target was to get that particular node drive.
Krish NAik: Okay. Okay, you are telling to open the browser, it works there. Alright, let me try to open the browser. If it works, it breaks, okay? So, just wait.
Krish NAik: I think so, if this is what we have.
Krish NAik: Sometimes it takes time to load up.
Krish NAik: That's true.
Krish NAik: Mmm, okay, alright.
Krish NAik: But here, also, if I directly see just where these are my old queries.
Krish NAik: Match-to-match query, like, anybody can paste me that query of match end-to-end here.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, I have to actually check it from the code of the last class.
Krish NAik: Anybody can build that full query up, like, star.
Krish NAik: That you do, if you remember. Anybody remembers that queries? Match NN in both the relationships, that I'll be passing it, because I don't think I will be having it in my history.
Krish NAik: Natural questioning…
Krish NAik: I mean, let me just pass it from Geron.
Krish NAik: Okay, I can see here. Okay, I've directly copied it from there only. I hope you get it.
Krish NAik: Guys?
Krish NAik: How many of you can see? Now, this is the, like,
Krish NAik: main one. You have to run the query without running the query, you won't be getting. But that's the main idea that I want to show you here.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, match P related to… okay, now you are adding the relationship types. Fine, like, if you want to add a relationship type, let me just delete all these things.
Krish NAik: Nice to meet you.
Krish NAik: So, this is what Jatinindar shared, okay? Now, this is all respect to relate it, okay? And this is fine.
Krish NAik: Oh, right, the entire one also you can look, so simply, like, write your query, and based on that, you'll be getting that entire thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can do the testing in your browser as well as in your local. In local, it takes time, okay? So, I know that after a few minutes, it will be loading up.
Krish NAik: Really not to worry about.
Krish NAik: Because the main purpose was actually to look into the depth, subnode, I can say, and actually, I reached that node, so I can say that this is better. Okay, so yes, with respect to the Napoleon info node, because, now how this is related with the main relationship one.
Krish NAik: The local URL is localhost7474, Satish.
Krish NAik: Okay, localhost 74, 74, just wait.
Krish NAik: Let me share the URL link.
Krish NAik: the last class…
Krish NAik: Just be sure you are passing the correct credentials, and it will work. All good.
Krish NAik: Fine. Now, this was the main purpose of that, particular operation, and this is actually a hybrid search now.
Krish NAik: going forward, see, I will say that if I say hybrid search.
Krish NAik: John, what should be in your mind?
Krish NAik: I hope for everybody it is clear that by default, it should come.
Krish NAik: Sparse vector, dense vector, and graph.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if you want to add multi-vector, that is also optional, but I'm telling you, like, 3 things by default. Fourth one, optional, it's fine. If you want to use cool butt and other stuff, it's good. Like, BGM3 models for that, if you want to use it, it's fine, but at least 3 things, parallel, everything you want to apply in a rack-based solution.
Krish NAik: Okay, then, keep a conditional routing logic, like, based on your query, try to analyze that, you can pass it to where you want to pass it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, like, later on when I'll be discussing Langrap, I will let you know much more in detail. But this is a high-level idea.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think I have done it.
Krish NAik: For… this part, okay?
Krish NAik: Alright, I will just… See if it can just do it.
Krish NAik: Now, guys, I will, now move to something different. No.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because this part, I have done it. Now, a little bit of discussion with respect to the company which promotes GraphRag the most in the market.
Krish NAik: That we'll be talking about.
Krish NAik: Ankush, you were raising your hand, is there some, like, Zoom issue?
Krish NAik: Was you not writing in the chat also?
Krish NAik: Name graph, okay, now this is…
Krish NAik: Now, when actually I look into MemeGraph, okay, this is also a graph database, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, and now, really, like, the first client when I say, is NASA. Really, like.
Krish NAik: And if you look into the clients, this is an older product as compared to… now, you have to understand, you can actually create this one, I feel that… good. Memgraph is also used widely.
Krish NAik: For graph databases, guys.
Krish NAik: The other one that I want to talk about is Falker.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the one, like, even…
Krish NAik: like, highly promoted one, I can say.
Krish NAik: Okay, the fastest… if you're working with graph databases, if somebody can do something, the fastest way, that is it. This is completely written in C language.
Krish NAik: I hope.
Krish NAik: If you're working directly on top of C, the speeds are better.
Krish NAik: as compared to even C++, if I say, hardware-level stuff, guys.
Krish NAik: any programming language, that's why I don't love Python. Python is pretty much a wrapper, wrapper, wrapper. That's why we generally work with Cython. Can you see GitHub trending number one repository of the day? I'm giving a lot of reasons for you, because this is really, like, one of the best ones, and
Krish NAik: How much research you want to do, you can always look into their blogs.
Krish NAik: I… okay, if you go into the log, everywhere you will see that they will be doing a lot of promotions. Okay, everywhere. But really, like, you have to always…
Krish NAik: Directly, don't blindly start reading their blogs and start doing the implementation.
Krish NAik: First of all, go through research, because everywhere I don't feel that you need to attach graphs.
Krish NAik: It's very specific, okay, and in those cases, they have
Krish NAik: implementations, how to build a knowledge graph, okay, as you can see here, this is also a good one. Now, from here, the concept of, like,
Krish NAik: few other things that came. It has a dedicated MCP server also, they have brought it, but this is the main company.
Krish NAik: Who highly promotes build graph-like organisms.
Krish NAik: Now, that's why I've taken a simple example here, okay, and please open your Notion, I think you guys can get it.
Krish NAik: Please open Notion, everybody. Okay, so here, Notion.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see a lot of main blobs, so, like, they have kept it here, but again, I… when I tell you that if you try to compare vector search with your graph rack.
Krish NAik: Again, control condition. Always remember this whenever somebody is publishing something with respect to, GraphRag.
Krish NAik: I feel that it's pretty much control settings. In the last class, also, I've told, like, directly on top of RAG benchmark data set, nobody does the testing. Everybody creates their own database, and through a control setting, they try to publish the result.
Krish NAik: That's the only con that I feel in academic research which has.
Krish NAik: Okay, can you see here, again, like, question, OWL ontology? Because everywhere, see, this ontology will come. That's why I want to focus, and I have given you a lot of prospect with respect to this.
Krish NAik: Because till the time, why enterprise queries need more than vectors, they have kept it. And can you say this? KG? KGLM? There is a concept of KG rag also.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me just, take one new tab, just wait.
Krish NAik: Okay, PG value.
Krish NAik: Can you say ateji.com.
Krish NAik: This is the KG rag, the knowledge graph rag. Okay, and again, like, KG rag, this is the graph…
Krish NAik: Another paper. See, GraphRad has a lot of papers, but really, like, which one to go at? This one. This is also a good paper, I will say. If you really are working, you can go through this.
Krish NAik: particular paper also makes a lot of sense, I can say.
Krish NAik: Okay, and a few things are there, which is pretty much unique. Only 5% new information in this paper, if you have already read the paper of GraphRag and OGRAG.
Krish NAik: But again, like, the upgraded version, I can see where they have really used some type of open data sets, and through that, they have done the evaluation.
Krish NAik: Because right now, really, like, I feel that there are more than now 200 RAT papers.
Krish NAik: Which are very, very famous. So I'm just showing you a few of those things.
Krish NAik: Okay, but, yes, this is a good one, I can say, if you really want to understand. Now, again, now, they have done the definition, they have shown everywhere. Now, with respect to enterprise-based operation, where you need to calculate KPIs, metrics, strategic planning.
Krish NAik: Okay, without knowledge graphs, with knowledge graphs, it means that whenever you bring knowledge graph, it means that you will be implementing some type of graph rack-based solution. They have told that, yes, there is some type of game.
Krish NAik: Probably,
Krish NAik: See, the way that they are referring is through a point, so I cannot directly say that, but overall accuracy, you can see, close to 56.2. Okay, without knowledge green, so I will say that, yes, it is working good, but again, enterprise settings.
Krish NAik: In enterprise, I know that it's not open-ended solution, I told you. Not purely open domain, like, anything can come. It's pretty much closed, so I know that for sure GraphRag will work.
Krish NAik: So, here it's given…
Krish NAik: Okay, then, schema dependency and entity density. This is also important, like, going forward, how many nodes you have, because with, respect to that particular decision, also, you need to take it. Okay, so graph rack, sustains stable performance. So, everybody, please go through this particular blog, I feel that.
Krish NAik: Though it's a little bit biased, but I feel that it feels good. You will get an idea, though they have tried to promote Falco DB, but I feel that it's important.
Krish NAik: Structural requirement, structural… the graph rag is a structural requirement. But structural requirement means, again, the same thing that comes, ontology.
Krish NAik: without ontology, you cannot define a structure, okay? And they have kept it in such a way that you can use it anywhere in your enterprise.
Krish NAik: Because, always going ahead with, okay, and, KGLM, okay, now this is the KGLM part that they have taken it. And directly KGLM Accuracy Benchmark is, again, not a open and generic benchmarking, again, very specific.
Krish NAik: only to graph rack-based papers. Okay, so that's why I feel that you can go through this. The main inspiration is that KG rack paper.
Krish NAik: spend some time, only 5 minutes you need to, and this is a very small one. Now, let's get back to my Notion, okay? So, in Notion…
Krish NAik: Okay, now, implement GraphRag with Falco DB. Now, this part, guys, I don't want to spend time, because I have already shown you the implementation with Neo4j, so can you guys do it, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Can you guys do it, yes or no? Because I feel that you guys should be smart, and by this time, you can see. Here, you have all PSOP code. Here, they are telling that what are the different nodes according to the data. Okay, so see, peep install FalcoTV, peep install Grog, they are using their LLM. Sentence transformers for using the embeddings.
Krish NAik: Okay, so pretty much simple stuff, it's not very complex, because I want you guys to do this
Krish NAik: after today's class.
Krish NAik: Because I have shown you in Neo4J, but I think you guys can…
Krish NAik: When I got disconnected, it looks like.
Krish NAik: Mmm, I got disconnected, I guess. Actually, in Bangalore, I have two backups, like.
Krish NAik: one geo, one act, here in whom I have only one of Wi-Fi, that's the main problem.
Krish NAik: Probably to just wait,
Krish NAik: Actually, in class, I use always the backups. Okay, now, see, I want you guys to do the implementation by yourself. This is Falker. So, you can do a local, like, same thing, like, NeoForge has a cloud version, which is called as the Aura.
Krish NAik: We have not explored, but I think you guys are smart by this time that you can do it. So, similarly, FalconDB, localhost, or you can use a cloud version also, because I want… I will be doing an execution of a certain notebook that I've created, okay? But,
Krish NAik: now the same routing logic and everything is there in LangGraph. I feel that it's not very much hard. Okay, so you guys can do it. This is also a simple routing logic. Okay, just like the notebook that I have used today. But, please try to do the implementation. The code is there, use AI, but at least just be sure, make it work.
Krish NAik: the speed in Neo 4chan, try to compare, like, if you want to really look into the speeds, Valkyr is, like, very, very speed, like, more than 100x faster as compared to Neo 4chan.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, this is how your final graph looks like, and I feel that this blog is a very, very good one. Okay, step by step, you can do the implementation, and new Forager part already I have taught, so switching graph databases should not be a big deal.
Krish NAik: So that's why, please do it. I think everybody can do it, please let me know in the chat. By yourself, after this class, this vlog, go to Notion. I have kept it in Notion. Implement GraphRag with Falco TV, Langshan, and this one. Okay. All right. Now,
Krish NAik: Alright, now, there is another high-level tool, which is a graphite.
Krish NAik: Okay, so a little bit about Graphite that I'll be talking about, because Gravity is another, I will say, tool, which sits on top of any vec… any graph databases, okay? So…
Krish NAik: Let me, show you… About, gravity, just to wait.
Krish NAik: Just tweet here.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Because this is another tool that I feel that people who are working with, graph databases, for them, it is very, very beneficial.
Krish NAik: That's why I want to talk about thermography.
Krish NAik: Notch.
Krish NAik: Graphic T,
Krish NAik: Okay, so building real-time knowledge, ones here.
Krish NAik: This is from where I got that, idea. So, there is a dedicated MCP server also. Can you see here, number one GitHub trending? Because, see, I want to tell you what are the things right now. Rahul is asking NotionSend. Notion is same, I'm not changing the Notion for the past.
Krish NAik: 5 months. Not generally the same route.
Krish NAik: You can go to the last section of today's date and check that part.
Krish NAik: Now, Graphite built real-time knowledge graphs. Now, this is what I want to do. Now, this is actually setting. Now, Graphite is just like a tool which sits on top of any graph database. Now, you have to check the integrations. I cannot say every database. Now, on top of which the integration is available.
Krish NAik: Okay, it gives you much more power. Dynamically, in real time, if you want to update any nodes and other things, those things can be done. So, like, I will say it's a good one.
Krish NAik: And generally, in racks, it is used. So, in high level, if I just go through this, like, what is GraphIT? Like, FalcoDB is a graph database. Similarly, NeoForge is a graph database, but this is a framework which sits on top of, graph databases, and manually, you can do any changes with respect to your main knowledge graph.
Krish NAik: So, Graphite is a framework for building and querying
Krish NAik: Temporally aware knowledge graphs. No, temporally aware means time. Temporal, when I say the word temporal.
Krish NAik: What is the meaning of temporal, guys?
Krish NAik: Like, if I say spatial.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody understands the term temporal, like, time-aware knowledge graphs. If I have something, properties, okay, based on some time events, this happened yesterday, yesterday at which time stamp, yesterday at which… like, if you want to create
Krish NAik: those type of solutions, where timestamps really plays a very crucial role. In those cases, it, really works very great. So, Jatindar is saying space last time. Space is different, use the term spatial. Time is different. Space graphs are different, and temporal graphs are different.
Krish NAik: So, don't use slash. Both the things are different. Keep it as AND, space, AND, okay? Okay, alright, for both, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is where I've taken an example where I'll be actually going through,
Krish NAik: live information which is available in Wikipedia, and then I'll be doing some type of temporal operation based on years. Okay, I'll be showing you that the notebook link I have already shared. You guys can…
Krish NAik: open that particular notebook. Please do check the notebook. I think I have shared one, yes, this one. Building knowledge graphs. Please do have a check on this Google Collab Notebook, okay? I'll be doing the execution, don't worry, but this is the notebook that I'm going to discuss.
Krish NAik: No, where is this one is?
Krish NAik: So, it's talking about, temporal-aware knowledge graphs, specifically tailored for AI agents operating in dynamic environments. Unlike traditional RAG methods, GraphIT continuously integrates user interactions, structured and unstructured enterprise data.
Krish NAik: See, here it's telling continuously integrates user interactions, structured, unstructured data, and external information to a coherent, queryable graph.
Krish NAik: Can I say that?
Krish NAik: It makes changes, or it simply makes changes to your existing knowledge graph. How many of you agrees on that? Because, exactly, it does that. But the param is basically based on time. Time plays the most crucial role here.
Krish NAik: So, actually, based on that, so time plays the most… crucial role.
Krish NAik: It's very, very important that if you want to create something based only on time.
Krish NAik: So then, I feel that Rafitti actually converts your normal, knowledge graphs into much more, like, a temporal waste, where you can create. So from here, the concept of temporal rack came into the picture.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, like I told you that temporal rack. Okay, so that's why these are the core foundation
Krish NAik: Temporal, right?
Krish NAik: Here, structured data is more like SQL or GraphDB.
Krish NAik: Structured data.
Krish NAik: Both it can be. So, don't think SQL, SQL data can also be created as a relationship-based entity. So, Mitesh, both the things.
Krish NAik: Because you can create graphs, knowledge graph, using new SQL data also.
Krish NAik: The simplest example I showed you, if you remember here.
Krish NAik: People, always, everyone. It's not like that you need to have NoSQL data. So, I think I opened this one, and I showed you the first thing in today's class, GraphRite.
Krish NAik: And this was one, example, I think, in… here on Ontology. Now, this information with respect to
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me just close this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's take the social media. Now, in social media, this particular information can be based on different tables also.
Krish NAik: Okay, now those… from those tables, you can actually get the data, and you can create your own knowledge graph. The main thing is that relationship.
Krish NAik: Multi-table relationship that needs to be defined.
Krish NAik: Oh my gosh.
Krish NAik: Okay, now… where is that part? Is it?
Krish NAik: Great.
Krish NAik: So, the framework supports incremental data updates. Incremental data update means live changes to your, graph database.
Krish NAik: And efficient, retrieval, precise historical, queries with requiring a complete graph recomputation. It means updating your graphs, graph schema, making it suitable for developing interactive context of our AI application. There, even you can think about, see.
Krish NAik: One important thing that I feel that, which is really important, that you can actually save the information about conversational systems.
Krish NAik: like, user, like, context of our AI application, it means that… that system AI conversation. In two ways, the system and the user is doing. That entire conversation, you can see a bit inside a graphic.
Krish NAik: But, I feel that.
Krish NAik: traversing GraphRag and keeping the same information somewhere in Redis.
Krish NAik: Redis is much faster, as compared to computationally
Krish NAik: doing it, because for most of my query and these things, I prefer to use Redis, but you have to understand, whenever you are working with Redis, it has a TTL parameter, the time to live, so…
Krish NAik: But in graph, it can be something
Krish NAik: consistent. So, that's where that is the added benefit, because I have seen people keeping the conversational data in
Krish NAik: gravity.
Krish NAik: in conversation… in conversational AI systems.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's take… This example.
Krish NAik: I think, whereas Notion is. Please open this, Collab one. Everybody.
Krish NAik: I think you guys can open this one.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please try to check. I don't want to open it here.
Krish NAik: Because I have the secret set, so a few things are there which needs to be configured here.
Krish NAik: I think Graphite Demo 26, yes.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please open the…
Krish NAik: Google Collab Notebook. Once you have opened, please let me know that done. Then I will tell you what are the next steps that needs to be done, because here you need to actually set your secrets.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… You have to set your secrets, everyone.
Krish NAik: How many of you know secrets?
Krish NAik: for example, your Falco DB, because I will be working with FalcoDB. So what you can do, go to FalcoDB Cloud, and you can create your own account.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if I go here, Falco DB, here I will go.
Krish NAik: Let's go here. And just create an account.
Krish NAik: You can create an account for free, so I will just do a sign-up.
Krish NAik: Okay, and generally, like, company email, you need to pass it?
Krish NAik: Yeah, so let me just try to do a login here.
Krish NAik: It has to be a company email, guys.
Krish NAik: I've not tested it, because it simply told me to bypassed a company win.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it's telling continue with Google, but, you know that, this account is different, just wait.
Krish NAik: So I'll go digging and sign in.
Krish NAik: Therefore, the Google account link to this, you know.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please, use your… How many of you, I think everybody has company accounts?
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: You have some type of domain, not the…
Krish NAik: At the rate Gmail one. That's the main priority.
Krish NAik: CPU, CPU, CPU, CPU. You can work with GPU, but I feel that it's not, for much, required.
Krish NAik: Yeah, okay, if Gmail accounts are working, it's fine, okay? Please, I have no issues, as they told company email, so I thought, okay, but you guys can check. If Gmail is working, that's great, nothing to worry about.
Krish NAik: Now, this is where you have to create an instance. It's just like Neo4J.
Krish NAik: Click on Create. Can you see here? The Falco DB free?
Krish NAik: Okay, so you have to just click on subscribe.
Krish NAik: Okay, once you have done the subscription, you have to click on Create.
Krish NAik: There are multiple plans.
Krish NAik: Please select the first plan, the Falco TV Free, and please use AWS. I prefer always working with AWS, so…
Krish NAik: This is fine, okay? So, I will just click on Create.
Krish NAik: Link to FalconDB URL. FalconDB URL?
Krish NAik: Means, FalconDB.com, are you talking about that one?
Krish NAik: 12, 30 pinks.
Krish NAik: This is FalcoDB.com. This is the main URL.
Krish NAik: Just wait, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I will just click on Create. Please sign up, and then Create.
Krish NAik: Okay, if selling passport is required.
Krish NAik: Here, I've not set any password.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you… any description is there, okay? So here you can pass… my crop database…
Krish NAik: Then, password, let's go with admin, 12345, and the name, Falcative instance, you can give anything.
Krish NAik: Falker DB instance is also fine. Now, you have to remember this Falker DB, which is the FalcoDB user, just like Neo4j. Falker DB and the DB password. Admin12345 that I have given for now, according to you, please pass your password. These things are important, guys. So, let me just click on Create.
Krish NAik: Okay, launching your instance, this is the instance ID. It's not necessary. If you look into, this is the same ID, so I will just click on close, and it will take some time for the instance to be initialized. Okay, so just wait for 3 minutes, I think within 3 minutes, it should be done.
Krish NAik: Everyone, please create the instance.
Krish NAik: Once the instance is done, then even I have to update it, so…
Krish NAik: Here, I have to update mine.
Krish NAik: Mmm, this one.
Krish NAik: So here, I'll be updating my secrets. You need your OpenAI also, your LLM.
Krish NAik: And now, how do we get FalcoDB underscore host?
Krish NAik: won't worry.
Krish NAik: I'll be telling you about host. So here.
Krish NAik: Let me see whether it got…
Krish NAik: We are till now deploying, so let's wait.
Krish NAik: Momes.
Krish NAik: I'm just looking into the sets your suite.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the default port of Falco DB.
Krish NAik: Which is 5717, okay, so one by one. User FalkerDV underscore username will be that.
Krish NAik: Okay, and password, okay, and this is Hajin face token, I don't…
Krish NAik: This is our… now, this will be generated, don't worry, once this gets created.
Krish NAik: Why it's saving so much time?
Krish NAik: Till now the lifecycle status is deployed, so just wait.
Krish NAik: Can you see this connect button is disabled? Okay, so that's what…
Krish NAik: Okay, now, the secret variables are available in your, here. See, check this slide.
Krish NAik: Here, Falco DB host, Falco DB port, Falco DP username, Falco DP password.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in your notebook, it's there, just check the cell above part 1, I think. Just scroll down a little bit.
Krish NAik: You will get that,
Krish NAik: Here. So, OpenAI API key is also required. So, total 5 things that needs to be attached.
Krish NAik: FalcatDB underscore host, FalcatDB underscore port, FalcatDB underscore username.
Krish NAik: Just wait. It takes time, like…
Krish NAik: Last time, it took around, I think, 3-4 minutes.
Krish NAik: This time, it's taking a little bit more. Let me just reload this page.
Krish NAik: Something went wrong.
Krish NAik: They're now deployable, right?
Krish NAik: For anybody, it got created.
Krish NAik: How do you get a secret screen? Secret screen. Secret screen here. You have to click on this one, this, lock, lock sign, the secret one. Click on that. Okay, you will be getting…
Krish NAik: Google.
Krish NAik: Okay, just wait, like,
Krish NAik: you need these four things, I'm sharing it in your,
Krish NAik: That's right, wrong here, okay, just…
Krish NAik: Let me just copy these things.
Krish NAik: And let me add it here, okay? So…
Krish NAik: Okay, so I even shared, you can reload the notebook. The notebook will be reloaded. So, these are the main ones. Falker DB underscore host. Okay, now the port is default one, guys, so let me tell you about the port.
Krish NAik: It's 57107. Okay, so the port value that you can actually add it is…
Krish NAik: 57017. This is the default one.
Krish NAik: Username, It's Falker DB only, if you remember. Okay, so… It will be Falker.
Krish NAik: DV.
Krish NAik: password. In my case, I think I have passed it something like an admin
Krish NAik: 12345 in my case, so whatever the password that you have passed. And host, I will be getting it, so once it is initialized, then only I can pass that one. So, let's wait.
Krish NAik: So, let me see…
Krish NAik: Okay, can you see here, now running it becomes? So, fine, now I think I can make the connection.
Krish NAik: Can you see here the host?
Krish NAik: See, you can… this is the UI opening, okay, but here, from here, you can copy the,
Krish NAik: 5.dv host, okay?
Krish NAik: what you have to do, just click on this particular connect, and it will open and copy this stuff. I think from other place also, connectivity, if you go, here also you can get the endpoint, in whichever way you want to do it. Okay, so that is to open the UI, you need those things, but copy this, even I will do the copy.
Krish NAik: See, copy, copy, copy, copy, all right here. Now here, what I will do, I have to update this one, so let me edit.
Krish NAik: Let's see, I will just… let me enable all the stuff here.
Krish NAik: Falcon.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, this is R- I know that this is the port.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, it got updated here.
Krish NAik: Then, admin1234557, this is fine, and this is FalcoDB. So, pretty much, I think everybody has received all the information. FalcoDB host, code.
Krish NAik: Username, password, please let me know. And actually, you can do a verification by,
Krish NAik: like, at least do check for one. You need the OpenAI API key also, guys.
Krish NAik: So, here you can pass, and you can pass your secret name. So, for example, if I want to check this one, copy.
Krish NAik: And this particular just pays the key.
Krish NAik: Just wait, I think I'm not connected to a runtime, but, let's wait.
Krish NAik: There is no specific reason, you can do it in your local laws.
Krish NAik: The same thing, just pass it in a .env file and other things.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is my sixth, okay, alright, now is,
Krish NAik: Not really, like, you can compare, that stuff with your next one, like… I think,
Krish NAik: I feel that he has these two things…
Krish NAik: Pretty much the same stuff, yeah, same things.
Krish NAik: You can always do the verification in that way.
Krish NAik: So you can always, print out all that user data, one by one.
Krish NAik: So, I think everybody has done the configuration, please let me know, can I move to the next step?
Krish NAik: Because I have not executed, neither done any installation. Please let me know. Can I move to the next step? Everybody has done the configuration?
Krish NAik: See, it should be in blue color, it should be enabled.
Krish NAik: If it is not in blue, you might get an error.
Krish NAik: It should be in blue color, guys, otherwise you might get an error.
Krish NAik: Do you… did you provide the secret manually? Yes.
Krish NAik: I just pasted the secret here.
Krish NAik: See, otherwise, if you don't want to do it, do it in your local. See, in your local, if you are much more comfortable, leave kola. The main purpose was, however you do it.
Krish NAik: just do it. I hope everybody gets the core panda. There is nothing… it's just like, we are doing it in collab. If you don't work with collab, do it in your local. I have no issue.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, the next step is installing Graphite Core and Falco DB.
Krish NAik: Can you… Ankit is asking, can you please show again how to get the Falcat DB host? Go to that, Falco DB?
Krish NAik: Okay, like,
Krish NAik: I will click on Instances, click on Instance ID, click on Connectivity, you will get the clipboard option, copy it and paste it.
Krish NAik: Handful.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me now do the installation of the main gravity package.
Krish NAik: Where we have to paste it? In your… where you have configured that, your Falker, your main key. These are all keys that I have. For this notebook, I am using 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 main keys. 4 are for Falcas, one is for OpenAI.
Krish NAik: You have to paste it here in the value part.
Krish NAik: Oh, great.
Krish NAik: For how many of you, this part is not working? If it is not working, simply take the implementation in your local.
Krish NAik: How many of you convert this implementation in your local? You have to add it in your .env.
Krish NAik: The packages are already available here, so you can do an… UV ad.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then this graphite core with Falco TV, this exact version that you can do it. If you don't want to do it in collab, switch, if you are having problems, because right now, solving collab issues is not my priority, but do it in your local, if you're not comfortable with Google Collab. Because I thought most beginners in the field of data science
Krish NAik: they do it in collab, so I thought about, but if you're not in that stage, leave it.
Krish NAik: Do it in your local. The main purpose is that it should be available here.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think the installation of the package that I have done. Now comes the model name initialization, so here I'm passing it. If you don't want to pass it in the secret hard-coded, as simple as that, guys.
Krish NAik: Don't think about anything just hard-coded. Nobody is accessing it.
Krish NAik: Now, see, this is the part where you need to hardcode. Please hardcode it.
Krish NAik: Okay, simply, just immediately. The main purpose of this is make things up and work. Later on, figure it out, how to make things. I think everybody can hardcode.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Don't spend a lot of time on this secret, and if it is not working, don't try to debug, directly pass your credentials, make things up, and work.
Krish NAik: All right. So, now I will be accessing the information. So, right here, these are some helper functions. These functions are responsible to extract some information from a web page.
Krish NAik: Okay? Later on, I'll be talking about… now, these are helper functions. The main purpose of these functions is basically to extract, information from your web pages.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let me make a connection to, Falker, and let me see that everything is working fine or not.
Krish NAik: This will take some time. Can you see here? Error connecting to this one? Name or service unknown? Fine.
Krish NAik: I will… this host is telling, and this is fine. I'm not worried about this one.
Krish NAik: I will hard code it. Even for me, I was getting an error, which I was not expecting. Let's see.
Krish NAik: Because the environment, it takes time, actually, to load up. Again, it's telling service unknown.
Krish NAik: Us remove… okay, okay, yes, yes, yes, port, port, put, port, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, yes.
Krish NAik: Actually, that port part, I need to remove it.
Krish NAik: I didn't saw that port part, yes.
Krish NAik: 5717 is the default one, yes, I can see now.
Krish NAik: Hmm… just wait, otherwise I have to add that.
Krish NAik: Just wait once.
Krish NAik: Because then I have to update that particular port that I am hard-coding it.
Krish NAik: You had a… yes, I think, because of that, code. See, whenever you are working here, just open that, here, like, get connected. You will see that this is the default port.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the port that you need to use there. So, in my case, like, I have pasted 5.7, that one, so this particular thing also, I will be hard-coding, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, let me hard-code it. Where is the part here?
Krish NAik: I'm just…
Krish NAik: So many things I have opened, even I get confused.
Krish NAik: Not this browser.
Krish NAik: This is not this one also.
Krish NAik: I think, yes, here. Okay. Now, in my case, what happened here, you can see the port. This port is picking up the 5701. Because of that, I was getting the issue. But in my case, what's the port? It's 62…
Krish NAik: Okay, 626262.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's take this one.
Krish NAik: Hmm… I will just pre-script, alright?
Krish NAik: Now it should work. There won't be any type of problems now.
Krish NAik: Yes, for everyone, it might be different, that's why, like.
Krish NAik: People, are you getting different boats?
Krish NAik: Everyone, last time I did a local one, I got 53772 already. Fine.
Krish NAik: all that stuff. Please do have a check, because this cell should be work, this is the main connection to your graph database. If this fails, rest of the things doesn't matter to us, okay? Please have a check on the database connection, it should be up and working.
Krish NAik: Alright, now,
Krish NAik: First of all, this is the Falker driver connection, okay, and you can see Graffiti is something, like, which sits on top of your graph database to make dynamic changes to your knowledge graph, okay? Graphite manipulates
Krish NAik: Okay, but the main graph-based operations are done by the Falker. Two different things.
Krish NAik: So now, let me start. Okay, now this is the information that I want to extract, okay? So, let me just open the Wikipedia page. Everybody, just go through the page and try to analyze, okay?
Krish NAik: I'll be extracting some changes here with respect to the table. This is from La Liga. Similarly, you can test it with some other football leagues.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, top goal scorer. Now, year by year, you will be getting that, information.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'll be extracting these type of… can I say that this is pretty much like SQL-based table? Because right now, it is simple, but I can keep this information in a SQL table also.
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Yes or no, guys? Because this is the same table that I'll be extracting it now.
Krish NAik: Okay, now you can see year-wise information.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first of all, like, I'll be looking into 2023, then 2024, and that way, I will try to extract the data from Wikipedia directly.
Krish NAik: Is Graphite like a wrapper here? Graphite is a wrapper, but that wrapper needs to sit on top of a graph database. So Graffiti has, integrations with, like, AWS, Neptune, Falco, New 4G, everywhere. You can bring Graphite and do the integration.
Krish NAik: A widget.
Krish NAik: For making temporal-based changes in your, database, in your graph database.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is, that I'm talking about, the La Liga main one. Then, what is the team that I'm targeting? I am only targeting two teams, which is the Real Madrid and Barcelona for now.
Krish NAik: And relevant date. Can you see I passed here date?
Krish NAik: Around 2023 till 2024.
Krish NAik: The dates are important.
Krish NAik: That's why the concept of time that I'm bringing into the picture, the temporal space within that graph database.
Krish NAik: You can focus on any other teams also of La Liga, but I'm just focusing on the major four famous ones.
Krish NAik: Alright, now I'll be extracting the data. Now, get standing table.
Krish NAik: GetStandingTable, now this is an helper function, getStandingTable here.
Krish NAik: from there.
Krish NAik: I've kept it, okay? So, these are… through some utility functions, I'll be accessing that information, okay? So, let me just extract it.
Krish NAik: Because if you really look into the mean code of utility functions, I have used simple pandas.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody is familiar with pandas here.
Krish NAik: Is there anybody who has no idea about pandas?
Krish NAik: Because here, say, pd.read.html. Yes, anybody is there who has zero idea about pandas?
Krish NAik: Because, see, guys, Pandas is something like datasets, fundamentals of it.
Krish NAik: So I'm not going to discuss about funders, if you don't know.
Krish NAik: like, majorly nobody is telling, yes, okay, few people are telling, they are comfortable with pandas, till now, not a single person who told, I have no idea about pandas.
Krish NAik: was the… Everybody starts, and then only 3 liabilities. They spill on.
Krish NAik: Pandas, and I think Matplotloop. These three are the major libraries that everyone knows in the field of data science.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, like, I've used pandas today. You can use any other, like, polars, fire ducts to do later optimization.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now…
Krish NAik: Alright, now here what I have done, see, from here, episodes 2, 3, you can print each of the variables, and based on that, you can get the information. So, from here, two items, the content, the team name, the real Madrid, can you see here? We'll be getting all that information, so you can actually, if you want, you can print this out.
Krish NAik: I'm not printing every information, but for your understanding, exactly the understanding of the code, you can print it and you can see, like, the real Madrid information and the Barcelona information that I am extracting. Now, that's why I've kept a simple for loop on top of these team names, one by one, that I can actually get and extract the information.
Krish NAik: Like, for I in this particular thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, directly on episode. Episode, inside that, I'm looking into that particular content, and I'm accessing this team.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the content type is actually the team name. Can you see? This is actually the key name through which I'm accessing the data.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Now, see, once I have this particular information, add episodes to the graph, now, this is the place, add episodes.
Krish NAik: Add episodes to graph, it means that I'm manipulating the graph and I'm doing changes.
Krish NAik: Is there? No, just wait.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the add episodes. I have taken episodes because you can think about episodes is a term which is based on time.
Krish NAik: That's why we are using the term. Generally, in… whenever you are working with temporal rack systems, they use the term episodes widely.
Krish NAik: Because episodes can be related with that T factor, the time factor.
Krish NAik: Okay, and directly, see, if I say a node.
Krish NAik: See, guys, if I say a simple term, nude.
Krish NAik: But if I say the term node with a time.
Krish NAik: some episode. How many of you get it? I will be using the term episodes here.
Krish NAik: Node with a time.
Krish NAik: Okay? So that's why in temporal rack-based systems, they prefer the term episodes much more.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first here, the initialization with respect to graffiti, the episodes, the group ID, and prefects episode, like, and with every graph note, I'll be adding that part. So, adding a list of episodes to the graph using graffiti.
Krish NAik: So, my knowledge graph that I'll be building, the first thing is that, the first step is to grade those nodes, and based on that, I'll be adding the information.
Krish NAik: And now, here, episode information. I am passing it now, this information, I am actually extracting it. Okay, and through this, I am actually… can you see here, graffiti.episode?
Krish NAik: And here, you need to have a valid connection with your Graph database, otherwise GraphIT cannot make the connection and make any type of changes in your Graph database.
Krish NAik: I'll wait.
Krish NAik: Let me just, do the execution here. I have shown you exactly what is there. Okay. Now, let's get the information from, 2024 to 2025.
Krish NAik: both the information, last one was from 2023 to 2024, and this time I am again extracting the information from 2024 to 2025.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, if you want to do the visualization, see guys, we have done the changes, so if you really want… So, what is your password? I think everybody knows. Please parse the password here and try to make the connection.
Krish NAik: admin12345, with a TLS secured connection, not required manual configuration.
Krish NAik: Okay, skip tutorial.
Krish NAik: Can you see here, guys?
Krish NAik: A graph which has been created.
Krish NAik: Everybody please try to visualize the graph. I've made up for… it's very much like Neo4J. It's not like…
Krish NAik: This is a graph database, so the same things you guys can do. Please check in the web UI.
Krish NAik: Jasinder is asking, how does one see using the web UI?
Krish NAik: I think, Jatinda… Okay, you're written here, so I think you got it.
Krish NAik: Yeah. Others, please do have a check. It's nothing… it's just the brother of Neo4G.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Episode C, generally, like, episode is just a term that we are using it. The main purpose is we were building that graph. Generally, in graph, we say node, subnodes.
Krish NAik: But here, we are telling that, okay.
Krish NAik: We are creating the subnodes, but with that time parameter. Because of that time, we are not using the term subnodes, rather than we are using the time much more episodes.
Krish NAik: So, now, if I try to go here, Real Madrid is connected to, like, relate, so you can see the same thing here.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, okay, 26, I can say that from somewhere, it, relates to 26, meaning sometimes, like, it might have own.
Krish NAik: La Liga 2023 and 2024 standings, second place.
Krish NAik: Okay, 85, probably, I think, 85 goals totally that they have met. Now, again, the same thing for Barcelon.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can actually do the visualization, and you can fetch the information. La Liga standing, the same thing, because this information and this information.
Krish NAik: It's pretty much the same one, and that's why there is a direct connection also.
Krish NAik: The blue color connection refers to the mention. Now, you can simply hide a few things if you really feel. I feel that the mention part is much more important. Real Madrid, Barcelona.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: And the connection through a node 1 here.
Krish NAik: And majorly, okay, all right with respect to certain matches. Okay, so always to try to analyze.
Krish NAik: And these are the pure nodes.
Krish NAik: Have a visual way of looking into that.
Krish NAik: No, later on, we'll be fetching that information through dates, Matesh. Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I've shown you a few things here.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, a lot of information that has been extracted, if you really look into the properties.
Krish NAik: Now, with every note, just check how many properties we have done it. Like, created ad, validate add, summary, expired at, invalid add, entity, name embedding, fact embedding, epi source, a lot of information that you are actually getting.
Krish NAik: Okay, now…
Krish NAik: This is based on episode. So, now, this is much better, I feel. See, till now, in the market for GraphRack, the best product that I feel is Falper. So, I'm just giving a…
Krish NAik: A simple example, that…
Krish NAik: If you really look into the UI, I feel the UI is also better than New Forge.
Krish NAik: Okay, and it really works out. Three supports are there, local, Docker, cloud, just like New Horsey also. Everything, pretty much the same things, and you can actually test it out. And automatically, the query gets generated for that particular thing if you want to work at. Okay, so you will see that it will be getting generated. So, I feel this is really good.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… in new 4K also, it happens, but this is much faster.
Krish NAik: Alright, now I have added both the things for both the information I have, okay?
Krish NAik: Now, let's look into…
Krish NAik: a certain, like, episode scores. Now, I already have that information, like, season 2024, 2025, this is a relevant date condition, and from that particular date, okay, I want to extract some information.
Krish NAik: Okay, so top score, so again, in the URL, what I am passing.
Krish NAik: the same Wikipedia URL, relevant date that I am passing.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the clear for C. This is the… Team data.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, I worked with the team data, the Madrid and the Barcelona. Then, in the next step, the top scorers. Now, I know that this top scorers is available where? In your…
Krish NAik: Yeah, somewhere your top scorer will also come. Team, or seasoned top scorer, okay, the main Real Madrid athletic commander is okay.
Krish NAik: Yeah… somewhere I know that top goalscorers are coming for which team?
Krish NAik: I can see that through this particular query, it can actually extract that, No.
Krish NAik: Let me get back.
Krish NAik: Yeah, yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, adding 3 episodes to the graph, again, the graph will be updated.
Krish NAik: Okay, and there is one future warning. This is from Panda's read, unless for its HTML will be deprecated, so nothing to worry about. So please do have a check on this part.
Krish NAik: Because right now, this parsing and adding, adding to a graph.
Krish NAik: It takes time, okay? So, fine.
Krish NAik: I can say this is an update to the graph, so later on, again, you can actually look into the graph.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the top scorer information. Top scorer…
Krish NAik: Mmm… GET…
Krish NAik: Now, see, here, this function is there, guys. Now, for this particular function, you can directly see this, that this is related. It means that this is my…
Krish NAik: utility function, which is already available, get top scorers. Can you see here? PD.read HTML. So, don't get confused from where this came. These are all utility functions, through which I am reading a web page, and from there, I am actually accessing that.
Krish NAik: Nope.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is taking some time, let's see.
Krish NAik: Authentication error, Satish is killing, I am able to establish, but getting below while running the next cell.
Krish NAik: Which one, where you are getting an authentication error?
Krish NAik: Authentication error, how many of you are getting any authentication error? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Output length exceeded 8192, could not parse the entire… okay, probably the content length was pretty much high.
Krish NAik: Got that.
Krish NAik: Yes, please let me know how many of you are getting authentication error. See, you guys might get an authentication error, but already I have added that line of code. Just be sure you are using these headers.
Krish NAik: If you're not working with headers, you might get an error.
Krish NAik: Because I think I have added the headers here, so I don't think any type of authentication error will be there.
Krish NAik: Please do have a check.
Krish NAik: Whoever is getting an authentication error, just be sure you are passing the headers correctly.
Krish NAik: Alright, now here I have done, and the top scorer information also that I got, okay, now you will see that this part will be updated.
Krish NAik: He's then moved… Here, let me see…
Krish NAik: Good afternoon, Laliga, good afternoon, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, Real Madrid, fine, with Real Madrid.
Krish NAik: Okay, these are the team members who have scored Okay, this is 31, alright.
Krish NAik: Related to move in.
Krish NAik: Now I'm adding one more relationship also.
Krish NAik: Okay, directly has member relate to?
Krish NAik: You know, like, because the graphs are really big, okay, and harder to visualize, but you can always play with these things.
Krish NAik: It will give you a much better idea.
Krish NAik: Relates to Barcelona with 85 written types.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine…
Krish NAik: Please do, because I have done the update, so whenever I'm doing this await operation, it means that this is a change in your graph, manipulating your direct Falco DB database.
Krish NAik: Satish is, can you show your graph? This is my graph. See, my graph can be different based on the query data I'm passing.
Krish NAik: Okay, then I will just clear everything.
Krish NAik: You guys can also check based on that.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, what are the things that I have in my graph database? One is the team information, and then I have the top scorers.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, the question comes, like, if I want to pass, like, what was real mother's final points at the end of each season? Now, this information…
Krish NAik: has been extracted, I think, from here, from the La Liga standings.
Krish NAik: I think these are the goals. Somewhere the point information, clubs, goals, average.
Krish NAik: Okay, Gold Play of the month, let me see…
Krish NAik: Somewhere at that point in average, attendance, all right.
Krish NAik: Because the point information's round.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me see here, because 1313…
Krish NAik: The results with respect to that.
Krish NAik: Let me see here, because Laliga, just… let me see this.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: There is a label, has season points. Okay, has season points, alright?
Krish NAik: Now, let me look into…
Krish NAik: High season points, high season points… Member Trust Fate Community.
Krish NAik: Because this should be visible, at least, just wait.
Krish NAik: Let me just make the connection. So many times I've opened it.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: The league table has the points, all right.
Krish NAik: Because right now, when I see that, valid from this particular condition at the end of each season. So right now, searching for this, Real Madrid said 95 season points. No, this is correct, I know.
Krish NAik: from 2023 to 2024, label from where actually it has fetched has season points. This is the actual, I think.
Krish NAik: the mood through which the relationship has been extracted. Now, these are sealing points.
Krish NAik: Now, the another level, this is 84 season points with respect to this. Now, can you see the timeline is different right now? Now, see, this is 07, 05.
Krish NAik: 05, okay, so 24, so 23 to 24, let's look into the years. 24 to 20, so this is next year, I can say. So 95 and 84, these two information correctly extracted. Now, Real Madrid has grub position 1,
Krish NAik: As, season, okay? Season position is 1 in the year 2023 and 2024. Real Madrid, again, 29 season wins.
Krish NAik: the… alright, 29 season wings. We get the total number of matches it has owned. So, every one has a different meaning. One is a season position, season 1 in here.
Krish NAik: Now, just look into the question that I have asked, how many of you feel that the results that you are getting from the graph
Krish NAik: is correct.
Krish NAik: Because a lot of other information also that you are getting, which is not relevant. Because really, my query is not related to, like, how many times Real Madrid has owned, like, in a particular year, I've kept each season. So, for sure, every season means every year that we can refer.
Krish NAik: Now, everywhere, every year when I am referring, I can say that the first two results which have been extracted, it's correct.
Krish NAik: The other three are also correct, I can say, but yes, semantically, they have a different meaning.
Krish NAik: Because season, every year there's a single season.
Krish NAik: Second and the fifth points are conflicting, alright? Now,
Krish NAik: Final points. Final point means, the total season points. 95 season points in the year 2023 to 2024, 84 season points here, this one that I have.
Krish NAik: Alright, now the fifth one has 26 season wins. Alright, now this is actually match, wins. These are points, and these are…
Krish NAik: So, both the things are different, Mitesh.
Krish NAik: Guys, see, here, you can check it with, change the team name to Barcelona and check the same thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, because here I feel that the points refer to total match points based on the standings for a particular year. The first two things make sense to me.
Krish NAik: The third makes sense, but we didn't actually ask it.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, what else was the position? So, this is a bit different, I feel. Fourth one, 29th season with total number of matches atoned in that year. Again, not the correct meaning based on the query.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, but I will say that the initial search results are good.
Krish NAik: Yes, points and wins are different, but it actually understood what does that mean.
Krish NAik: Because, see, the portion that I asked was very high level.
Krish NAik: Later on, it actually broke it into parts.
Krish NAik: So, this is where I feel that it's much more robust.
Krish NAik: Alright, now,
Krish NAik: Now, this is another form, through which you can add more, nodes to the existing graph. So, if you really look into… this is another news information that we are adding it with respect to Barcelona.
Krish NAik: And Manchester United, I feel that in this information, we are taking it from an article of ESPN. You can look into the article, we are fetching the information.
Krish NAik: And let me pass it here. So, another note that we are actually adding it, like, this is the article preview, and finally, only one episode to the graph, it means that through and one node that I can actually access it.
Krish NAik: Now, who are the players rumored to move in Barcelona? Okay, now this one…
Krish NAik: This article actually gives you that information, like how many players moved from Barcelona to Manchester United.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the high-level information that I was actually planning to get at. Okay, now…
Krish NAik: I think I've already added that.
Krish NAik: Okay, Hannah, let me look into that.
Krish NAik: Okay, Mark Oregon discussed about Marcus Rashford's potential move to Barcelona after Spanish club were given permission to speak to the player.
Krish NAik: Alright, this really looks good, because now I have done everything based on a query. How many of you feel that this can be helpful? Because this is a real-time information that I have added it into the notes, and I have fetched the information.
Krish NAik: real-time information, I fed it to the graph, and then I performed an query.
Krish NAik: pretty much temporal. When I say temporal, it means with respect to time, I am doing dynamic changes, and then I'm making the query.
Krish NAik: there are many use cases where you find that this will be useful. And really, in enterprise, I can say that it will be useful. So, just think about, there will be many, many use cases.
Krish NAik: So, it's making web search.
Krish NAik: Right now, I…
Krish NAik: I'm passing the URL directly, but you can think about… you can make a web search. From there, you can actually gather the data, but you have to do the refinement of that, because multiple URLs will be getting Raul. Out of that, you need to figure it out. What is the final thing that you need to add? Add an episode into the graph.
Krish NAik: Because the same information can be there for multiple URLs. So, you don't need to add multiple URLs to that note. Make your one final selection, and based on that, try to do the information, or add the information in the note.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is node-level search directly. Now, this is, handset flick, another clear name directly. So, based on a clear name also, you can pass the information, okay? So, a similar information that is available here.
Krish NAik: Similar nodes, like other, node information. So, this is the final node result. You can see this is the main query. This is the other way. Now, see, this is how directly you can use gravity.
Krish NAik: graffiti.underscore search. Now, this is another
Krish NAik: like, search using graphic design. These are not Falker operations, these are Graphiki operations.
Krish NAik: I feel that Graffiti is actually a very famous
Krish NAik: not a very famous, a very robust one, which is having a lot of functionalities, and you should actually use it in production. It has a lot of valuable use cases.
Krish NAik: And that's why, like, in the research part also, you can see that a lot of other things that will come. So, here it's telling such the latest news about Manchester United.
Krish NAik: Alright, so Ruben Ameren is the coach of Manchester United.
Krish NAik: Mashford spent the last two weeks training away from the first… okay, now, these are all things which are getting, extracted. It means that you can update your graph in real time. How many of you get this thing?
Krish NAik: Updating graphs in real time.
Krish NAik: This was the main thing that I want to… PQ.
Krish NAik: And that's why I brought Graphite into the picture. Graphite makes your life much more easier by helping you to make manipulation to your direct knowledge graph.
Krish NAik: Okay, make the changes, queries, the rest of the query is directly, like, simple graphs, DB-based query.
Krish NAik: Real-time updates, so more and more type of updates that you can actually… so, first of all, like, again, I am adding some, type of, I can say nodes, and then again, I am performing. So, you can keep on updating, and you can keep on performing and growing. So, these are much better, I can say. So, more examples, I've kept it, rest of the things you can explore.
Krish NAik: Okay, but, please, start integrating, because this is the first day that I've discussed, but try to plan a use case where you feel that you need something real-time.
Krish NAik: And based on that real-time information, if you want to fed it.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can actually think about. And this information…
Krish NAik: You think that once you have kept it, it means that it becomes a persistent information.
Krish NAik: Not like in one run it is going. Whenever you are adding some information in the node, just think about, in future also, it might have some…
Krish NAik: It's not like that for the sake of just to perform a web search, okay?
Krish NAik: There should be a good logic of adding something to your node.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that in future, again, you feel that it is required.
Krish NAik: Just for one search, don't do it. It should be something on the repetitive basis that you feel that it makes sense, and again, it might be, queried up. Then only it is…
Krish NAik: Architecturally, I will say that it plays, then, a crucial role, rather than a simple thing.
Krish NAik: Alright, guys,
Krish NAik: Real-time updates, generally, I will say that, fetching the data from the URL and updating the drop database, yes, for sure it will take time.
Krish NAik: But now the question comes, an end user will never update the graph. You will do it.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because he will be doing that thing, so the end user. So for him, the speed will be much faster.
Krish NAik: In our case, we are adding it to the graph database, so it's taking a lot of time, okay? So, now look into that, because…
Krish NAik: Yes, it can be managed, because we won't be giving any end user to manage the, to do any changes into the GraphDB, but I feel that real-time updates are important in graph database.
Krish NAik: Because in a vector, fine. In a vector rag, if something is not fine, you will do a web search. The same logic, you can apply it here also. But what about permanently adding that information?
Krish NAik: All right, guys, so I think for today, only these things that I want to discuss, okay, and it's already one, I know I have extended the session, but, a lot of things with respect to Grav, because GRAPRAG, again, a very… till now, a lot of research has been going on, okay? Because, I think last week I was reading a lot of papers.
Krish NAik: The recent paper with respect to graph phones, I can say this is the Hyperbolic acid. Okay.
Krish NAik: This is the recent one, the latest paper that I was reading.
Krish NAik: Because, rag papers are just like, people are throwing it, okay? Now, this is an advancement of normal grab rag.
Krish NAik: Okay, and how, hyperbolic rag is getting into the pictures. It means that they are changing the dimensions with respect to, but how to make your multi-hop traversal better with some type of reasoning effect.
Krish NAik: So, that is where I feel that, and…
Krish NAik: So, in just, like, last week I was exploring this one. There is zero racks, so many racks, okay, but
Krish NAik: If you have something like that. I recently saw, like, light… light rag is good, no. See, light rag, you can actually use…
Krish NAik: Lightrag is from?
Krish NAik: HQ Doers. Okay, so… light ride. See, HQ doers, when I say, how many of you know about HQ Doers? Previously, also, I've told you in this batch, HQ doers, the Hong Kong
Krish NAik: University. Research lab.
Krish NAik: These guys, they have that open data lab, they have good OCRs, everything is good.
Krish NAik: They have rag anything, this is also, like, a very famous one, LightRAG. You can pick up, because these are framework guys. Can you see RAG anything? If you're working with multimodal data, it has a lot of things, but again, VLM, NS, query, and other things, you need to take care of. Graph-based multi-knowledge.
Krish NAik: No.
Krish NAik: Again, like, a dedicated paper also they have published about RAG anything.
Krish NAik: for any Novice users, that's very, very good. So you can explore these things.
Krish NAik: HQ2S is a research group, actually, just like Stanford, MIT, CMU, they have their dedicated, and this is a good one. In, I can say in India, there is not a single group which is very good.
Krish NAik: In Korea, there is CAAST, K-I-S-T, it's good. In China, they have, 3 major good ones.
Krish NAik: Shenzhen is there, okay, in Taiwan, there it is, Singapore, it has, okay, and one in Hong Kong. Other… in this part of Asia, I don't feel there are many other search groups which are
Krish NAik: into this particular research with respect to RAG and other systems.
Krish NAik: Alright, so guys… I'll be, concluding the session for today.
Krish NAik: No, Rahul is, okay, alright. So many frameworks. Yeah, it's not possible. More than, I feel that in the market, 200 to 300 papers of rag is done.
Krish NAik: You just need to look into wherever which is much more widely used.
Krish NAik: Okay, pick that one and start using it. Later on, you can make changes in your core RAG engine.
Krish NAik: But I feel that in a rack engine, the…
Krish NAik: 40% poor functionality doesn't change it.
Krish NAik: Few thing changes. 20-30% that can be kept as an optional module, and click on updating it.
Krish NAik: wait time.
Krish NAik: No, nobody can say it, say Rao. When you say so many frameworks available, which one to use? Why? Why, like, when you pick up something from research, now the question comes, are you a research guy, or do you want to use something in production?
Krish NAik: Production guys directly blindly start using
Krish NAik: Yeah, like, Langchain, Langraph, Llama Index makes your life much more easier. You don't have to do anything. For research, guys, where you feel that I have 6 months of time?
Krish NAik: Then, for you, I can say start exploring LightRag, ApoRag, so many things are there. Research is different, application is different.
Krish NAik: So that decision needs to be… it means that if I have a project, in how many months I need to deliver? One month, nothing. I'll be picking up something, drag-and-drop-based solutions.
Krish NAik: 3 months, yes, I will write my own custom modules, I can do that and plan it.
Krish NAik: I have one year to deliver something, then I will make a team, I will do the research.
Krish NAik: So it always depends upon time and revenue. These two are the important factors to pick up those type of decisions.
Krish NAik: Alright, just wait, Mudassar, I will unmute you.
Krish NAik: Just quick, okay? So, not this, rahul… yes, go ahead.
Mudassar Hakim: Thanks, Paul. So, Paul, I get the part, right, between the production thing and the research thing, but kya Ogana.
Mudassar Hakim: At the end of the day.
Mudassar Hakim: I will also have to do a judgment, especially for production. What is the stability achieved for a certain framework? Before which I can say, gicholor, now let's use it. Because, obviously, every day… I mean, this is something very similar on the front-end libraries also. Every day there's some new library coming, becomes top, and then eventually some other comes and overrides it.
Mudassar Hakim: But we, AK, we look at key, cholo, we have one-year stability, we have good, uptick on the stars, or upwards, community support, and then we take a chance to cholo, let's go with this. So, with that perspective, you know, going ahead with these, different frameworks of RAG,
Mudassar Hakim: Do we have somewhere to look up all these things, or is it something… we just wait for some stability to happen, maybe in the next 2-3 years, and then take a call?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, see, take something, don't use anything that is 6 months. I don't pick up anything in my production, at least 1 year or something.
Krish NAik: I don't pick up anything that is recent. It might be very, very good. I might be implementing it in my main pipeline, probably after one year. I just always wait and watch it.
Mudassar Hakim: I feel that any implementation is there. If it is very, very good, always remember it will be picked up by the major frameworks.
Krish NAik: For example, CRAC, corrective rack, self-reflective, these are something that had become a standard. Everyone, LanChain, they have implemented it, Llama Index. Then I know that, yes, this actually makes sense. First of all, it should make a valid sense. It should not be highly controlled paper.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you look into the outputs, and if you feel that it is very much controlled in an controlled setting, it means that everything is a custom thing that they have put. I don't prefer directly to pick up those implementations and in my pipeline that I suggest, but I feel that there are certain things which make your life easier, because New Forager was there.
Krish NAik: Graffiti is pretty much new. I can say for the past 1 year, graffiti has been
Krish NAik: But, I feel that gravity makes sense.
Krish NAik: When something makes sense to me, yes, I will include it in my pipeline. It might be new, because I know that once it has become, it will become stable after one.
Krish NAik: And later on, a fulfilled product, a properly, pricing plan, and everything will be… probably my,
Krish NAik: product. Price might be increased, I know, but the solution will be much more viable, and with respect to time, I can add much more optimizations to my product.
Krish NAik: So, always look into Langchain and Llama Index Community, how they are looking into these things. They give you the right track. Always look into the repos which are at least having more than 25K stars.
Krish NAik: That is the starting point. I know that it has become a data science standard, I think.
Mudassar Hakim: Anything like 500 stars, 100, 200, 2,000.
Krish NAik: Again, it means that the community is growing, growing.
Mudassar Hakim: Great, yeah.
Krish NAik: And there are certain things which are overhyped in the market, like open road.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, the creator of OpenClaw, like, open…
Krish NAik: simply has to learn… use me in production. Use it for your own person, because everybody is setting up open…
Mudassar Hakim: Then that idea also got extended now, right? Now, we have similar versions in Perplexity, similar versions in Cloud.
Krish NAik: genius.
Mudassar Hakim: Where they have replicated the idea and said, shallow boss, forget that, take ours.
Krish NAik: everybody, the Nanoclaw, so many, like, the same replicated projects with better security versions that they are trying to bring it. But I feel that, sustainability, that is the main thing.
Mudassar Hakim: Hmm.
Krish NAik: rather than, like, doing the research in a controlled setting, in an environment, publishing a paper is different. It's part of PhD, and so many PhD candidates are there. They need to do something, I can understand. But, really, like, applicability, I feel like very less papers are there, which are practically, like.
Krish NAik: moved to production. That's why people in PyTorch community do more research. TensorFlow community, exactly. Put things and rating. That's why I prefer TensorFlow for
Krish NAik: production things, because they're… they don't update things so much. Very less updates in TensorFlow. PyTorch, every day, every hour, every minute, I can say somewhere in the world, they're doing some changes.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah.
Krish NAik: But for researchers' good.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, okay. So yeah, I just wanted to see, I mean, definitely, I would have loved to see you creating something like a LLM or Arena kind of a page where you can say Paul's selection, you know, and I could refer to that. But anything else beyond that.
Krish NAik: Maybe later on, see, probably in my next work, like, as people have started much more, probably, like, now if you have the people, you can start the implementation majorly, like, in Langchen or anywhere, right?
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, like.
Krish NAik: Because I'm planning for my next one, it's better to create, just take the paper, look into the main part, how to do it, and use AI, and convert it into. Because, I just want to… I was looking into one of the major implementations of RefRag.
Krish NAik: Anybody has heard about Refrak? It's a really good paper that came from Meta last year, because Meta
Krish NAik: Really releases something game-changing, but they never release the source code.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, what happens now? Making something standardized becomes a problem. The same thing happens with Jepa and real Jepa.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'm just sharing this one, refrag. This is really a good paper, Refrak Meta.
Krish NAik: Now, the official implementation, rethinking rack-based decoding.
Krish NAik: You will see that it gives a different perspective to your normal rack thinking, and it's really good. I feel that it's good. But again, with respect to the actual implementation here, it has given. See?
Krish NAik: Okay? Page, not found. Now, this is…
Krish NAik: Because in another batch, I gave a task, okay, he told, no, I know the GitHub link is here, I have seen, I don't know. Initially, they launched it, later on, they removed it very, very quickly. Now, I feel like this implementation is good, and it can be actually moved into production.
Krish NAik: But again, the standardized, once they make it standardized, then actually we can adopt it.
Mudassar Hakim: I mean, let's see how it goes. We are trying to see if we can productionize things, give that level of confidence to our stakeholders and clients, key, this will work from a longer-run perspective. But we othayana, day in, day out, we are getting so many new things, and definitely good ones, nonetheless. But.
Krish NAik: Now, does a rag is something like, even, see, adopting, I know, but you have to be very much active in that CRA.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, that… a little bit, because you need an RN team, little bit, at least two, three guys.
Krish NAik: Who will do that little bit R&D? Because I can ask the AI for… But that's an ongoing thing.
Mudassar Hakim: That is one…
Mudassar Hakim: No matter which, area of work, whether it is Java or Node, everywhere, that same thing applies. Point is that, to what extent, they say apneg Bata, right, 25K stars, what is my statistical threshold beyond which I now decide to absorb it or consume it? Now I know that, yes, it is good. Not from an opinion perspective.
Krish NAik: 25Ks, like, really good, but there are others that, once they feel that even 2,000, 3,000 stars, they start adopting it.
Mudassar Hakim: Because you know how clients are, right? Nowadays, clients are like, okay, get me things working. They are kindly… they're kind of okay to digest a certain latency and delay on things, but they get it when it sees working, right? But if I try to experiment by bringing something new, and that starts blowing up.
Mudassar Hakim: Eventually, then, credibility comes into picture, that, boss, you only told me to put it, now things are breaking. So, we start wondering, okay, is it worth it or not?
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, that exactly is the problem that I was about to discuss, you know.
Rahul Parihar: So, I'm doing a POC… sorry, I'm cutting you off, you want to continue?
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah.
Rahul Parihar: So, there is a POC that I'm conducting, Paul. I wanted to talk specifically about… this is mainframes, you know, mainframes…
Rahul Parihar: data conversion from Absetic to ASCII is a use case. So what I've done is I've kind of qualified what level of, level of use cases that gets qualified for an AI infusion, and that AI infusion
Rahul Parihar: We'll make a strong case study that, the current work that the team does is, say, 1300 hours, you know?
Rahul Parihar: With a RAG implementation, which is a common, rule-based engine, which could…
Rahul Parihar: Store this conversion mechanism, and then take the data, read this rule engine, and convert it.
Rahul Parihar: But productionizing… see, I'm doing a POC right now.
Rahul Parihar: So, I have to ask you this question specific about the RAC pipeline.
Rahul Parihar: And, some of the external services, and when to call, because we don't want to share any database set of information, so that will be definitely guardrails and stuff, put in in place.
Rahul Parihar: So, my caution here is… One is the cost.
Rahul Parihar: The volume of data that gets transferred,
Rahul Parihar: Would you prepare… would you give some advice on productionizing it?
Rahul Parihar: at what metrics to capture, like, from a, from storage perspective, from the transactional throughput perspective, from token capturing perspective, one of the docs that you shared on AWS Infra.
Rahul Parihar: was really useful, but it says, like, 1000 token, this much, you know, price, or consumption on database side, or on external services side, on Wrike pipeline side, how to optimize that. So…
Krish NAik: That… that is my question, you know, like… See, context window allocation is a separate thing. For example, whenever I'm working with my tokens, there is that context window allocation whenever I'm working with token management.
Krish NAik: optimizing the number of tokens, I can do that through…
Krish NAik: token pruning. Now, what is your main objective? Like, to reduce the.
Rahul Parihar: The main objective is to first… first understand key what… it has to be AWS native, so what are the key rack pipelines for document services that we can use within AWS, within, like, embedding, or…
Krish NAik: that is something other. That is not related. You can use so many services, it has, like, everything that AWS has separately. NLP-based services, text track, anything that you get.
Krish NAik: Parsing part, easily you can do it. Now, let's come to the next part. After parsing, what do you want to do?
Rahul Parihar: performance characteristics. I wanted to identify that, what would be the latency of the search, or, this much, this much embedding I'm trying to… Steve, I wanted to use…
Krish NAik: I'm saying, S3, S3, simply let's talk about right now, as you're talking about, performance characteristics of what? If I say, with respect to VectorDB here, you have only two things, S3 and OpenSearch.
Krish NAik: Very bad.
Rahul Parihar: Pretty bad pricing, yeah.
Krish NAik: Okay, now generally what happens, I will prefer to go to AWS Marketplace. Let's pick up something as a third party.
Krish NAik: Because AWS native solution is not optimized, it's not to really try to check the… a simple latency from there in, like, in millisecond you will get it, that, yes, there is a simple difference by making it weird. So probably moving to a third party is a better option, or let's focus on doing custom.
Krish NAik: like, let's take a proper dedicated cluster, and let's post quadrant or milliverse in our own. That will be my choice. Two things.
Krish NAik: Pick it?
Krish NAik: Okay, now I will say that at least you will be getting much better, that part. Now, once you have somehow resolved this part, you have posted your own, and you are doing. Now, alright, fine, let's take after parsing somehow that you have moved to that step. Now, the next step is that your main, I can say, retrieval step.
Krish NAik: In the retrieval step, like, NDGC, MRR…
Rahul Parihar: Yeah.
Krish NAik: Few other metrics are there through which the mean retrieval metric, not the
Krish NAik: those things, like faithfulness, keep those things later on. Right now, if you are trying to create a benchmarking system, I think you should create, according to your own set of documents, that at least how fast the queries are. For those things, you need to work on those metrics.
Krish NAik: Okay, now those are the internal rag retrieval metrics, just like RUG1, ROG 2, Rogue 3 that you have in your pure NLP, in your deep learning NLP, Meteor 1,
Krish NAik: a few things you can take it from there, I can say that for your internal benchmarking, but,
Krish NAik: Those are specific only to rack-based systems.
Krish NAik: Okay, like any GCC, I feel that it plays a very crucial role.
Rahul Parihar: The problem here is, they are so AWS-bounded, you know, the companies that adopt AWS is just so…
Rahul Parihar: So, narrow thinking on AWS that this platform is providing out-of-the-box solution, and I disagree with most of them.
Rahul Parihar: See, if I use an AWS S3, Lambda, or a Bedrock, and an OpenSearch service, my cost explodes, you know? Or Aurora Postgres service for retrieval, for example. My cost explodes.
Rahul Parihar: Because the kind of data that I'm trying to pull in, but how to modernize it with and leverage
Rahul Parihar: Say, for example, you said, use VANA, you know, to pass it and call your LLM, for example, you know?
Rahul Parihar: So, between the AWS native services versus the open source services, how to run that open source services within the AWS set of infrastructure, there is no direct channel that they have opened, right?
Rahul Parihar: So they want to use your own… they want to use… they want to sell their own services. They don't allow that, thing to work it so streamlessly. So my point is.
Rahul Parihar: How to make that…
Rahul Parihar: Differentiation from a cost and performance characteristics perspective, that's the going to the open source solutions.
Rahul Parihar: may not be secure, but may be optimized. So, what is the kind of…
Krish NAik: I got your point, C.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah.
Krish NAik: simply, like, as you are trying to say, who in AWS will never say that, which you are telling.
Krish NAik: Now, it's the job of the DevOps guys.
Krish NAik: You will pick up that this is an open source solution, and for example, if you want to make it scalable, let's start with something, like, you want to host it. You will host it in your own Insta. This is how the whole world works.
Krish NAik: Okay, nobody uses all the services of AWS. It's actually a bad practice also, you don't need, because
Krish NAik: I cannot do… like, if I want to bring, most of the times, I prefer hybrid cloud solutions as well. Something from Azure, pick up the best one, pick up the best things from GCP, pick up the best things from AWS, and try to bring that. But sometimes, when it's only AWS-based, it means that you have to hold something open source. It means that you need some dedicated pods.
Krish NAik: within a particular Kubernetes cluster where that particular open source service is running, or whichever library I can see.
Rahul Parihar: Correct.
Rahul Parihar: But what are those libraries, we cannot use Super Babwe, like, it's banned in India, for example, for a reason, right?
Krish NAik: Hmm… Receipts.
Rahul Parihar: 4?
Krish NAik: few things in open source which have been standardized, you can use it. If I really… if you want to use Superbase.
Krish NAik: super well, because I can serverless.
Krish NAik: Once… that's the other one which that got… I think Noon is the other name.
Krish NAik: the upgraded version, which Database right now, I think, brought last month, or around that time. Nune is another, just like Superbase, but again, serverless. Serverless Postgres was that one.
Krish NAik: Because, see, if something is banned, there will be an alternative buying.
Krish NAik: now you have to look into that open source alternately. Like, if you will say that Superbase, then I will move into something like Neon is there. A few things are there, but I feel that…
Krish NAik: Hosting again, probably AWS databases, I will never pick up, it's very, very close.
Krish NAik: Rather than having my own hosted, Postgres is much better.
Krish NAik: He lied.
Rahul Parihar: hosted your own Postgres, yeah.
Rahul Parihar: So, how did you arrive to that particular page that you have put together for AWS infrastructure to come with the pricing, you know, and caching,
Rahul Parihar: How did you arrive to, say.
Krish NAik: I pasted around, first of all, I fetched a few URLs.
Krish NAik: Those URLs actually are pasted in Cloud.
Krish NAik: Okay, first I did my main research, I filtered out the URLs, and then I passed it. It means that majorly all the URLs for AWS blogs, from those blogs, I picked up
Krish NAik: Okay, and then I actually created this one, the native one.
Rahul Parihar: So, can you share that, that markdown file, or the prompt that you created to generate that page? Maybe that would be giving me a.
Krish NAik: That conversation will be, like, very, very old. I have to look into my, conversations in Europe, probably I will get it, but, it's a little bit old, you know, like, two things.
Rahul Parihar: Bedrock 10 million embedding is the $100 cost. That is the price, like, Bedrock.
Rahul Parihar: 50 million input token size, these prices loops, where are they coming from? What are their monthly production breakdown that you have given, right?
Krish NAik: Alright, with respect to that pricing, pricing actually differs. Every organization, because I've given a rough one. Why? Because when you actually do a deal with AWS, your pricing and my pricing will be different.
Krish NAik: If you have committed to AWS for 5 years, your pricing different, 10 years different, 15 years different. So, that's why that pricing will be different. That price, I cannot directly say it.
Rahul Parihar: No, no, I'm trying to say, if you have a cost breakdown on an estimated monthly production, I agree. You are saying $2,118 per month, you know, on Bedrock, on OpenSearch, on.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, yes. That part I can actually.
Rahul Parihar: I'm sharing it with you.
Rahul Parihar: But I'm… what I'm trying to say is, see, are… you know, the enterprise pricing model will be different for company to company, and my usage…
Rahul Parihar: on what parameters, if I plugged in my usage, my monthly cost will change, so I have to build up a calculator to plug in that this is the usage of the use case 1, this will be my monthly cost. Use case 2, this will be my monthly cost. Use case 3, this will be my monthly cost. Like that.
Rahul Parihar: You getting my point?
Krish NAik: Yes, I'm getting.
Rahul Parihar: So, I need to design something like that, you know, to…
Krish NAik: Okay, I got it. So, let's take a simple example. Okay, generally, like, even I do it when I suggest, at least for, like, based on Mao, DAO, okay, based on certain things, I take a rough estimation and tell that, okay, at least, like, monthly, this is, annual this is… you need a rough calculator like that.
Rahul Parihar: Correct, correct. A rough calculator, not a…
Krish NAik: Got your point, got your point, got your point. Like, I know, like, it doesn't matter, like… Something, yeah, something around… Okay, fine, generally, for pitching, I do have that particular document, or I think my data guy has it. I can share that document. I have that. At least for AWS, I can share with you, okay?
Rahul Parihar: Okay, okay, thank you, thank you, sir. This will be a very helpful,
Krish NAik: Because that is with respect to, you know, probably a few services that might not be, but I think that solution… because it's not for AWS native, we have to understand. It can be hybrid.
Rahul Parihar: Hybrid also, yeah. Whatever Ivnim's trying to convert, and she's just trying to show, this is the AWS price, this is a hybrid crisis, this is an open source price, how much prices difference does it make? But, you know, the architecture changes drastically if you change from.
Krish NAik: No, no, see, it won't be like that. It will be fixed. I know that this is the architecture, and this is the cost of this architecture. Because when I say someone.
Krish NAik: it means that this is my final, document that I'll be sharing. It's not like that after 3 rounds of discussion, every round, not that document. I can share that finalized document, like, this is the architecture, this is the cost, this is the calculator.
Krish NAik: Now, according to your own pricing, you can change, like, one, rest of the things will be same. Now, the Mao Dow will be based on mine. Okay, but it will be fixed, it's not like that, comparison, like this and this. That won't be there. Okay.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, at least I'll get a starting point, you know, to get my head around that, you know, so if you can share that…
Krish NAik: Already, fine, fine, fine, fine, fine, that item. Thank you.
Rahul Parihar: Thank you. I'll drop you…
Krish NAik: John is there.
Krish NAik: Ishan, Ishan?
Ishan Pande: Paul, can you hear me?
Krish NAik: Yes, Ishna.
Ishan Pande: Yeah. So, I'm Chaitan, actually, I just logged in with my son's name.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, okay, chat, okay, yeah.
Ishan Pande: Yeah, so… so in my organization, there is one use case around this, graph, database, okay?
Ishan Pande: And it's like, we have codebase in mobile and RPG, and this legacy system is going through a modernization journey, okay? So we have code repository, we have got business scenarios in place, right? Especially, like.
Ishan Pande: For example, trade, okay? All business scenarios, what data it takes, what output it generates, some output, some upstream system, some downstream.
Ishan Pande: Then we have got test data, and we have got test scenarios.
Ishan Pande: Now, so we are trying to generate a…
Ishan Pande: We are trying to fit this database
Ishan Pande: to a graph database, and then trying to
Ishan Pande: Generate a relationship, which can be eventually used for
Ishan Pande: impact analysis, or test discovery, right? If I'm introducing XYZ change, then what is the impact, and how should I plan my, testing? How should… I mean, how should I understand what upstreams are impacted? And then, accordingly, the things will be driven, actually.
Ishan Pande: But, based on the sessions I've attended from you, it seems like this
Ishan Pande: canonical representation, linking, and all should be followed, right? But just thought to understand, like, first of all, is it the right use case? Like, is it a good idea to process all the code based from a repository, feed it into a database, and write code?
Ishan Pande: Find out the.
Krish NAik: I can see that in your case, for sure, the… let's take a sample… any type of project, or any type of database that you are working with.
Krish NAik: I will say that it's static, it won't be changing, that's the benefit. If something is not changing, you can create rules. In your rules, for example, main source code with respect to modules, in that way, you can define your node, actually.
Krish NAik: I'm giving a rough idea.
Krish NAik: So I can say that if something is not changing, you can go ahead.
Ishan Pande: I see.
Krish NAik: And in your case, it…
Ishan Pande: Yeah, but what everyone is looking for is, like, now it's a code repository, and very frequently would be…
Ishan Pande: seeing that core repository as well. And then, based on that, we should… Like, what is the impact?
Krish NAik: See, first of all, when you are telling that every time it will be changing.
Krish NAik: I mean, see, are you talking about something which is already working for the past 20 years, are you doing that, or something completely new you are bringing? Because if you are bringing something into the new, then you can add it, like, just now I showed you. Through time or rail updates, you can bring that, but it should have some value into the system.
Krish NAik: If it is totally, like, not valuable, then adding that as a subnode to your graph doesn't make sense.
Krish NAik: If you feel that, yes, the codebase is getting updated, it's fine. But, see, whenever you are making an update, you have to think that, okay, then this node
Krish NAik: just like a simple git commit just saying, if something got updated, Git tracks, but here, you have to manually, it means that probably you might need to delete an older node, and you need to replace that node with a newer one.
Krish NAik: These things you need to take care of. If you feel that your code wheel that is changing.
Krish NAik: That graph of details…
Ishan Pande: Yeah, sorry to interrupt, yeah, don't work.
Krish NAik: You tell, you tell, whatever intelligence.
Ishan Pande: So, see, so, but at the moment, see, let's say I'm just dealing with one repository, which has got thousand plus files, okay? And then organization wants to scale this up at an org level, basically, right? Like, it should be a knowledge repository for all of our business lines, and then that way, we should be
Ishan Pande: Able to leverage it for any of the changes we are doing in the organization, okay?
Krish NAik: But for your every database there will be different graph databases, no? Like.
Ishan Pande: Tim.
Krish NAik: It means that under Falker, we'll be having multiple drop indexes.
Krish NAik: Also, for every project, you can actually maintain a separate index, just like in different, just like VectorDB, you have multiple indexes or collections. The same thing applies here also.
Krish NAik: Okay, you'll be having multiple graphs for your multiple databases in the same builder. If you have 10,000 projects, you will have 10,000 graphs.
Ishan Pande: But, like, based on what you have explained us, I feel like it is a good idea to only keep the business-level information and stay away from the code, actually, right? Because otherwise, we will end up eating a lot of tokens, and that cost will increase as well, right?
Krish NAik: you can keep that if you feel that it's not changing in every interpret. Like, for every Git commit, I won't be doing that.
Ishan Pande: Oh, boy.
Krish NAik: as simple as that. If you say that my codebase is statically, like, every time it's changing, I won't be taking that. At least to a certain point. Probably I will update the graph, but after at least one week or two weeks. I will take time for that graph update.
Krish NAik: I hope you get my point. Like, at every… just think about everyday developers are working, and they are making close to 30 commits. Bad practice to dynamically update the graph in that case. Take your time, take a certain cron job that every one week, according to your updates, how much you can see, then based on that, make an update.
Krish NAik: It makes sense much more in graph rack.
Ishan Pande: Okay, perfect, yeah, thank you.
Krish NAik: Alright, guys… actually, okay, fine, because I got a JD…
Krish NAik: From one of that. If people are looking for switch for graph-based solutions, okay, I think this is one from Nagaru, it came. Otherwise, tomorrow I can share that part. Tomorrow, let's talk about. Most of the people have dropped, I think.
Krish NAik: Tomorrow, I think we will start with Haystack.
Krish NAik: Mmm, that's top 3. Just wait.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: Hmm, not this one, where is that?
Krish NAik: No worries.
Krish NAik: So I think this is the one…
Krish NAik: No, this is a staff engineer backend.
Krish NAik: people looking for a target. Again, like, people who are interested, you can let me know, I will share this one. This is a direct… the company guys has shared this one with me, so people who are interested, okay, you can drop. And just be sure you are good in that, okay?
Krish NAik: This one, because he can, estimate around.
Krish NAik: to an HR package also, you can write what is your… is anybody interested, then only I'll be sharing. If somebody is not interested, simply I only be sharing with them, okay? So tomorrow, just let me know in the starting of the class, I will share this.
Krish NAik: They're… right now, in the market, it's very, very hot, and people are making switch. This is a very good time.
Krish NAik: to change your package, like, people having moved from 20 to 30, 40, 50 people are paying anything to hire, like, right guys, anything. Please try to make a switch. This is really a good, good time.
Krish NAik: I know people with very less knowledge, they are making switches.
Krish NAik: Okay, so start, taking that action, and I feel that,
Krish NAik: RAC 2.2 will come, but you guys don't need to enroll in RAC 2.0. You guys will be enrolling in that advanced one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for this batch, RAC 2.0 is not necessary.
Krish NAik: About, like…
Krish NAik: Because, so tomorrow, I think NVIDIA GTC event post also, I need to share that also, I forward, I think. Probably fine. Tomorrow in the morning, just two things, let me just keep it as a need.
Krish NAik: Parajna asked me to share that, but yes.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so let's meet tomorrow. Tomorrow, we'll be talking about Haystack.
Krish NAik: A stack, pretty much like Llama and Langshan Bros, but much more, I can say, abstract.
Krish NAik: everything will be there in imports. So, pretty much high-level import calls that we'll be making it tomorrow.
Krish NAik: So tomorrow's class, optional, like, for everyone, I wouldn't suggest learn Haystack.
Krish NAik: But again, for production, I've seen that,
Krish NAik: In production only, KStack is used a lot.
Krish NAik: So, if your organization has taken that decision, then yes, it's easy.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so let's meet, tomorrow and continue our discussion with Historat.